Hello and welcome to this lecture, where you are going to learn the differences between object tracking
and object detection.
Sometimes both terms are used as if they were the same, but there is a very important difference,
mainly regarding how the implementation of the algorithms was made.
In general, tracking algorithms are much faster than detection algorithms because it should track and
object.
The algorithm already knows what it looks like in order to track it in the next frames of the video.
For example, let's suppose that the goal is to track the runner to the and off the track in this frame
here.
We already have basic information about the object, and when you are in this position here where I
am pointing the mouse, we can use this information about the features of the object.
And also the algorithms can detect a kind of patterns that indicates the direction and speed of the
object.
The runner is following the track from left to right.
So the algorithm already knows that in the next frame of the video, the person will be here.
In short, this information is used to predict the location of the object in the next frame.
For this reason, tracking algorithms are faster because they use existing data, whereas a detection
algorithm would have to be executed from scratch frame by frame without reusing data.
It would take a longer time to execute.
On the other hand, tracking algorithms can have a little difficulty in tracking objects that change
position drastically.
For example, if in the next frame, the person appears below here instead of following the straight
line.
In this situation, it will be difficult for the algorithm to follow the object.
If there is a video composed of 100 frames, a detection algorithm will run 100 times once for each
frame.
On the other hand, are tracking algorithm will detect the object only in the first frame, and then
it will use that information until the end of the video.
When you start working with some algorithms, it is common to have some problems.
For example, in this image here, see, that's the bounding box moves away from the object, and it
can happen when the speed is very high.
And the algorithm loses contact with the object in this other image here.
See, that's the lag of the runner does not appear very well due to the speeds.
Therefore, the algorithm can also have difficulties in tracking the objects, and the bounding box
was placed higher.
To solve this type of problem, you can try different algorithms.
Some of them are suitable for faster videos.
Later in this class, you will learn a lot of algorithms and we will be able to perform some tests related
to this issue.
Another solution to this problem is to use a detection algorithm again.
Sure.
Is that the tracking algorithm?
For example, when this bounding box here loses the object, we run the detection algorithm again,
chalkboards.
The building blocks in this position here again so that the tracking starts again.
Later, we will implement tracking less detection.
Finally, a tracking algorithm can adapt to small variations in the images in the videos.
For example, in these cases where the person boards here are her hands in front of the face, a face
recognition algorithm would probably not recognize the faces.
Why?
What tracking algorithm would still be executing correctly?
It happens because a tracking algorithm considers the location and.
You rinse off the object in the previous frame.
In the previous frame, the algorithm identifies that the dispersant here did not have his hands in
front of his face.
And when the person puts the hands in front of the face, the algorithm will continue tracking.
In other words, the algorithm already has the information for the right part of the face here, which
was obtained from the previous frame.
This animation shows the differences between tracking and detection, as you can read here.
Tracking preserves the object's identity.
Once the algorithm starts tracking, the object is treated as a single entity.
For example, look at this orange point where I'm pointing the mouse.
It has this same color from the beginning to the ends of the trace.
It's the same object and it indicates where the object is going.
On the other hand, the detection only analyze each frame of the video.
It's not possible to follow the path of the object.
That's all for this lecture.
And then the next one, you will start learning the basic intuition about some tracking algorithms.
See you there!