Hello and welcome to this lecture, where you are going to learn the basic intuition about tracking
algorithms.
First, you will understand that intuition and then we we implement then step by step using Python and
OPC Library.
We have this image here where the goal is to select the runner and track him should the and off the
track that are actually part of concepts that are used in almost all tracking algorithms.
The first is called motion model, which is a combination of location and speeds in previous frames.
So based on the location blurs speeds, it is possible to predict the next location of the object in
the next frame of the video.
We have the current frame here with the building blocks around the object, and the prediction will
indicate that in the next frame, the object will be in that part of the track where I am pointing the
mouse.
This second concept is the appearance model, which, as the name suggests, is responsible for storing
the object's appearance.
Or this shape should search for locations close to where the object will be in the next frame.
Then, nearby positions, some searches will be performed around the object, where I am pointing the
mouse to predict the next location and speeds.
Let's suppose that in the next frame, a car appears in this position.
The appearance model will check that's the appearance of a car is totally different from that bearings
of a person.
They have different shapes, so the algorithm will continue tracking only the person.
Here we have a summary of these two concepts.
The motion model predicts the approximate location of the object.
The appearance model adjusts the location to provides a more accurate location based on the appearance
of the object.
And in general, algorithms use both techniques together.
The motion model blurs the appearance model.
The purpose of a tracking algorithm is to classify a rectangular region as an object.
Are the background of the image, which is everything in the image that has no relation to the object
that we are tracking.
For example, in this image, several boarding boxes will be created here, here and here, and the
algorithm will receive an image batch as inputs.
This is through immunology that represents information about the big cells of the images, and it will
return our value in the range from zero to one.
That represents a probability of the area being the object or the background of the image bit closer
to one.
The more likely it is to be classified as the object.
On the other hand, the closer to zero, the more likely it is to be classified as the background.
Each one of these rectangles is an image batch that will be sent to the algorithm, and then we can
get the probabilities, for example, than present here 80 percent here and Tampa-St. here.
As the person is in this central part of the track, we have a higher probability in the middle box,
which is the real direction of the object and the prediction of the algorithm.
So in short, the algorithm we will receive as inputs the image batch of this surrounding possible positions
that the object could go and will generate a probability.
For each one of them, and the highest value will be the selected location of the object in the next
frame of the video.
Tracking algorithms can be developed using chalk machine learning techniques, online learning and offline
learning.
Most algorithms use the first approach they are trained in real time and at runtime.
The training starts when the algorithm is executed and all mathematical calculations are done during
execution.
On the other hands, thousands of images are needed to train and off line classifier.
For example, should track cats and dogs.
It would take thousands of images of cats and dogs so the algorithm can learn from the images before
tracking them.
Online learning is faster and training starts when you select the object you want to track in the next
lectures.
We will implement so it will be easier to understand.
And that's all for this basic content about object tracking algorithms.
And in the next lecture, you will start learning the intuition of some tracking algorithms.
See you there!