Hello and welcome to this lecture, where you are going to learn the basic intuition about true tracking
algorithms.
And the first one is boasting, as you can read, here it is.
A low algorithm does not work very well.
It's not so efficient, and it is based on the higher cascade classifier with the other boost algorithm.
This is the algorithm used for detecting faces and objects with open CV.
It is one of the simplest techniques for detecting objects.
Training is online, meaning that learning happens when you want to track and object.
It uses the concept of positive and negative images.
The positive image is the object you want to track, while the negative image is the background.
For example, in this image here, you must create the initial bounding box by selecting the objects
to be tracked, which is the positive image.
And the rest of the image is the negative part.
That does not have the object.
For example, the house, the wall, the people here.
And so one each part one.
If it is the object and zero, if it is the background, we can redo the definition here.
The initial bounding box this blue building blocks here is the positive example, and the rest of the
image is treated as the background.
The negative examples we can consider that this image is the first frame of the video, and this one
is this second frame in which the person has his back turns.
See that we still have the blue bounding box that indicates the object and choose author orange boxes
were created, which are the negative examples.
Of course, more boxes will be generated and not just chew.
The next step to continue tracking the object is to generate the probabilities for each one, and the
one with the highest value will be considered as the positive building blocks.
Here, the blue box adds the highest probability compared to the others.
It's similar to this slide here, where the goal is to select nearby bounding boxes and return probabilities
to each one of them.
And that's all for the basic intuition about boosting.
The next one is m i l multiple instance learning, and generally it has better results than boasting.
The training is quite similar and see that in this image, we have the positive examples in Grimm.
Let's suppose you selected only this region of the image where I am pointing the mouse.
Then the algorithm itself creates either balding boxes to increase the image area, as you can see here,
that are two additional bounding boxes instead of using just one positive example that are several orders
that are created automatically on the order hands.
Negative examples These red rectangles here are also created far from the positive examples, each short.
Rather than just considering the object's current location as a single positive example, the algorithm
looks for positions around the current location to generate several, but they show positive examples
scenes that are three positive examples.
The probability of selecting them is greater than if we had only one positive example.
Again, as for boosting probabilities will also be generated and only one bounding box will.
Is selected to continue tracking the object, this other image show this process in more detail where
you can see the positive X samples that are around the face of the person shift to the right and shift
to the left when the prediction is made.
Only one of these regions will be selected is the one with the highest probability.
We can also look at the negative X samples that are far from the positive X samples with this parts
of the shoulder of the person.
The advantage of this algorithm, if compared to boasting, is that even if the object's current location
is not found, exactly.
If we use this order, balding box is here, we can still tracking the object.
And that's all for this basic intuition about this two algorithms.
And in the next lecture, you are going to understand the intuition show.
So more tracking algorithms see you there.