Hello and welcome to this lecture, where you were going to learn the basic intuition about two other
tracking algorithms.
The first one is key C.F. kernel correlation futures, which is a fast algorithm.
However, it doesn't perform very well, especially in fast videos.
And one of the most common problems is when the building blocks loses the object.
As you can see here and here, GAISF is an extension of an AI algorithm that presents some improvements
and considers that in the AM AI algorithm, there are many overlapping regions, as you can see here.
One box can be created above all others.
So Cases aims to solve this problem, so this image shows an example of how it works.
We have here the first frame, which is the initialization are the definition of the objects should
be detected when working with videos.
We use the first frame to select the object we want to track.
Let's assume that we selected this red frame here.
For example, the goal is to track this face.
So the algorithm applies a concept called particle filter.
As you can read here and show, more large bounding boxes are created to cover a larger part of the
image.
Here the blue one and here degree in the one next front frame choo choo frame three.
The larger rectangle is used the green one, and some mathematical calculations are made to adjust to
the frame in this central part of the face.
As you can read here, the filter is updated, then from frame four to frame five.
The blue filter is updated to this centre position off the face, then in the next frame.
This same process is also made now considering that Reds bounding box after finishing the first update
of all filters see that this size of the larger filter has decreased slightly.
The green one?
See here in the original image that the border is the next should this frame add to the background and
here the position is quite different.
So it was adjusted to the object when the other side.
You can see that the boarding box has been moved here where I am pointing the mouse.
The goal of the algorithm is to make several adjustments in these boarding boxes in order to circle
the objects and be able to detect it.
The larger frames are in part and should detect changes in this scale are the size of the object.
For example, if in one frame the object is smaller and in the next frame, the object's increases in
size like a person approaching the camera.
Now let's go to the basic understanding of the C SRT algorithm, which means discriminative correlation
filter with channel and spatial reliability.
It is more accurate than c f, but is is lower.
This image shows the steps of the algorithm in the first box.
Here we select the object we once should track.
For example, only the person's head C or this third batch, which is widely used in computer vision
and is related to the information that was selected from the image.
Information about the big cells of the image.
Then in this step number two discriminative filter is graded and the hawk a histogram of oriented gradients,
that clinic will be used and it will extract the most important information from the image and.
Discards everything else, a hog will also identify the edges and corners of the image.
Should this cover this shape, for example, the hand is shaped like a Sirico in the third step.
A random MERS-CoV test is a blight, which is a mathematical concept to predict the next image.
See here that we have the same shape as the image as if it were the person's next movement.
In this step, probabilities will be generated to indicate the person's movements.
For example, if the person turns his face to the other side in this part two here, that's the prediction
will be made in order to verify if the movement is off this person.
So that's the algorithm continues tracking.
Finally, in a staff member for a confidence map is used in the image.
We have only the object with a mask, and at the ends we have, the complete object should be tracked,
as you have noticed.
This is a more complex algorithm that uses several computer graphics techniques, and the purpose of
this lecture is only to present an overview.
If you want to know more details, you can read this article for more information in the next lecture.
You are going to learn some more algorithms.
See you there!