Hello and welcome to this lecture, where you are going to learn the basic intuition about far more
tricky algorithms.
The first is medial flow, which is not suitable for fast moving objects or objects.
That's changed their appearance quickly.
For example, if in one frame the object is far from the camera and in the next frame, the object is
too close to the camera.
The main concept of the algorithm is that it tracks the object in four words and backwards directions,
and measures the differences between these two trajectories.
For example, in this image, we have the previous frame and the posterior frame to know the next location
the object will be.
The algorithm calculates the difference between them, so we know if the object is following the trajectory
correctly, the algorithm is not suitable for objects.
That's changing appearance, according to this definition here, because of this calculation of similarity
between frames.
If here where I am pointing the mouse, the runner changes its trajectory upwards towards the grass.
The differences between the trajectories will be too large, and it will not be possible to continue
tracking based on this calculation.
It is possible to predict tracking failures or when the object leaves its position.
In this example, you can identify if a runner is going out of his or her lane and is invading someone
else's lane.
This image shows how the algorithm works.
We have the previous frame, the minus one.
The current frame leathered the here and the arrows indicate the direction of the next movement.
This other image shows the calculation of the median, which is a statistical concept to calculate the
differences between frames.
If the difference of the media is this small, the object is heading in the same direction.
On the other hand, if the difference of the medium is big, the object has changed direction.
This is why this algorithm is called medium flow because we are calculating the direction of median
values.
The next algorithm is the L.D Key Learning Detection.
This diagram shows the structure of the algorithm, which is composed of three parts drag key learning
and detection, according to its name.
The first step is to start tracking the object, and while the object is being tracked, the data is
Sand's should the learning process, so it adapts to tracking.
While the algorithm is learning, it is online learning the object detection process is improved and
the detection data is sent back to the learning process.
When tracking fails, the algorithm tries to learn from its errors and sans the data should try to detect
the objects again.
We are not going to see mathematical details as the goal of the course is just to show a general overview
of the algorithms.
The next algorithm is most minimal output sum of squared error, which is one of the fastest but not
so accurate.
It's a good option if you need tracking speeds and don't care so much about quality.
The algorithm is robust to lightning variations.
For example, if the light is on in the first frames and the light is off in the others, it's robust
to scale.
If the object is near or far from the camera, it is.
Also robust to pose, for example, in the first frame, the person is facing the camera and in the
next frames, the person has his or her back to the camera, or when the person puts their hands in
front of the face in order to identify this changes in the environment.
The algorithm uses a mathematical concept called correlation filters.
This image shows how the algorithm works.
In the first frame of the video, you select the face or the object you once should track.
It is the initialization phase.
See that the image is quite dark and in the next frame.
When we increase the light, the algorithm continues tracking the person's face frame.
One hundred and fifty and frame two hundred and fifty.
These Reds point indicates the center of the detection.
And here we can see more information.
We have the inputs, which is the object, the application of the correlation filter and the outputs
with the result of the object that was tracked.
We can see only this centre point here and here.
Finally, the last algorithm is golden, which means generic objects tracking using regression networks,
which was strange using off-line learning.
This is the only algorithm with this feature.
We have seen so far, so it was strange using datasets composed of thousands of videos.
It is based on deep learning and convolutional neural networks, which is a type of neural network widely
used for image classification.
Here we can see the architecture of the algorithm, which starts by the definition of the object you
once should track.
As we can see here, this image is sans show five convolutional layers and three fully connected layers
so that we get a prediction of the object's location.
The neural network returns a balding box, as you can see here, with the position of where the object
is in the next frame.
Don't worry about understand the neural networks because as I mentioned before, the goal of the class
is just to show you the basics of each algorithm and you can access the additional materials if you
want to know more.
Wolters doesn't have very good results because we need to track objects like the ones the algorithm
was trained.
For example, it will not be able to track fingers because it has trained with the hands images.
So before using it, you'll need to check the objects.
That's the algorithm has been trained on.
Of course, you'll need to perform some tests to see if the algorithm will perform goods in your application.
Finally, we have a summary of some of the algorithms C s r d has the best performance.
Birds is this lowest case.
CRF is not very good regarding quality.
However, it is a very fast algorithm.
On the other hand, Mus is the fastest of all.
It is important to note these features of the algorithms for you to choose the best one according to
the type of application you are developing.
There are some applications where you need a lot of precision and the speed is not.
So that's important.
So you can use C s r d.
There are also some applications where the quality is not as important as this builds, so you can use
case the f r moves in the next lecture.
We are going to start with implementations, so there.