Hello and welcome to this lecture, where I'm going to show you how you can install Anaconda and by
charm on your old machine seals, all examples will be implemented using both tools.
You can access the Anaconda website, as you can see here.
Let's click this option here.
Then you can download it according to your operating system.
We can see that it's possible to download for Windows, Mac and also Linux.
When you click this button and the installation file will be downloaded and you must run it and follow
these directions.
I'm not going to show you this process step by step because it's basically following these structures
on this screen.
In case you don't know, Anaconda.
It is one of the most used tools for programming in Python, especially for working with artificial
intelligence and data science.
The advantage is that several air specific libraries are already installed, and it is also possible
to create environments with different versions of Python.
For example, one environment using Python two and another environment using Python three and one environments
does not influence the other.
Then the next step is to install by Sharp, as you can see here, which is an IEEE for working with
Python less click downloads.
Let's choose the community version, which is the free version when you click.
This link and installation file will be downloaded, and you must run this and follow the instructions.
Again, I'm not going to show you the process is a step by step because it's basically following the
instructions on this screen after installing it.
You can open by sharp great this button here.
New project Then you can select the location where you are going to save the project.
For example, in my case tracking, let's keep this option.
New environments using one that select Python version, for example.
Three point nine and then let's create this last button here.
It will take some minutes to create the new projects.
You may see this screen here.
In this left part, we can access all the files.
And in the center part is where we are going to Typekit the codes.
Now we need to install open library in order to have access to the tracking algorithms.
We can create this button here.
There are, and let's type PIP install open CV by press and there.
We can see here that it is downloading the library and also installing some dependencies.
Now we need to install another library.
Let's type again.
You install open civil country Python.
We need this country package to have access to the tracking algorithms.
Let's press and through again.
We can see that it is download and install needed packages.
Now we can perform a test just to make sure the installation was done successfully.
Let's click in the name of the project's Neil by phone fail.
Let's call this first fail fast open CV.
Let's start in part CV two, which means the library we have just installed lets type see visual thoughts.
Version we can Gleek run fast, open CV nowhere or was returns, so it means that the installation was
done successfully.
We can just prints the version of open CV we are using.
Let's run this code again.
See that we have version four point five point four, and in the next lecture, we are going to start
implementing the algorithms.
See you there!