Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to start the implementation of tracking algorithms
using open civet library.
Just a reminder that last lecture we created this file best open CV.
Just to make sure that the library was successfully installed.
Now let's create a new file and we'll click new Python file, and the name of the file will be single
tracking.
The first goal will is to select and track only one object.
Let's sequence the libraries import civic.
Sure.
This is the open CV library in part, cease to have access to some functions of the operational system
from random import rounds and to generate random numbers.
Now I will create the first variable tracker type in the format of a list.
When we open and close brackets, we are defining a list in Python and the goal is to define here the
name of each one of the algorithms.
The first one is the most in the next one.
Am I al key CRF?
The next one, the EL the medicine flow moves.
And finally, see SRT.
This is the algorithms that we saw last lecturer's, and we are going to use this list to define the
algorithm that we are going to use less great than other variable tracker type.
This first one will change the name for tracker types, and in this other variable, we are going to
select one of these algorithms.
Let's access, for example, tracker types in position zero.
Let's bring this tracker type.
We can run this code just to perform the first test.
See that when we put numbers zero, we get the name, which is boosting indexes in Python starts from
zero.
Boasting is the algorithm zero and I l is the algorithm number one, GCF algorithm, number two and
so on.
Let's put here three.
Run this code again.
See, that's the result is the the position zero one two three.
We are going to use both variables in order to indicate the algorithm.
We are going to perform the tests.
Let's implement and if state dement's, if tracker type equals Boorstin, then we are going to create
the object.
I will create this other variable.
Tracker equals switcher.
Let's access this package legacy dot tracker boosting the underlying grid.
This is the way we can create each one of the algorithms we can.
Breen's the tracker.
But first, let's just change it to here to position zero, which is the boosting algorithm.
Let's run this code.
See here that we have this information tracker Boorstin, and this ladders here indicate that the object
was successfully created.
So now we have a boasting tracker in these variable here.
This ladder represents the address that the object is occupying in the memory of the operational system.
Now we need to perform order if state demands to create the order algorithms.
L If tracker type equals m i l, then the tracker will be equal.
Q Stevie Sure, legacy dots tracker m i l create l if tracker type equals Keith's.
Then the tracker will be quote, you see.
Legacy tracker key c f grade, you can't see that we are always accessing this same package now if tracker
type equals the next one.
The LV banded tracker will be equal to CV Q Legacy Tracker the LP create the next one.
If tracker type equals median flow, then the tracker will be equal to see fit your legacy tracker.
Median follow.
Create.
Al, if tracker type equals the next one is the WEWS algorithm, which is the fastest.
Then the tracker will be equal to spiritual legacy tracker Moos.
Great.
And finally, let's move on to the last algorithm L.
If dragon type equals C s r d, then track your equals c ritual legacy tracker.
C s r d create.
And just to make sure that all objects will be created, let's fast one by one.
The first one is the boost in the next one m i l.
The information here about the object means that it was successfully created the next one kiss.
See if we can see this error message because here we need capital ladder.
That's the first one here tracker.
And let's correct for the order algorithms.
Let's run this code again.
Now the object was successfully created.
The next one.
Number three, the L.D number four.
Median flow number five.
The Muse algorithm.
And finally, number six, see as our D we can see here the message indicating that the object was created.
This is the first step to implement object tracking.
We are creating different objects.
According to the algorithm, once you perform the tests and the next lecture, we will continue the
implementation.
See you there.