Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to continue the implementation of single track.
Just a reminder that the last lecture we implemented these codes to select the algorithm was for use.
And in this lecture, we are going to read the video that we are going to use as example, and then
we will select the object that one should track.
I will create a new folder here, new directory.
I will call the name of the folder will be videos, and you can access the class materials and copy
and paste this file race thoughts and be far less.
Click OK here inside this folder.
We will start all the videos that we are going to use in this class.
You can see the video here.
The goal well is to select the objects are the runners, and then we are going to track the runners
until the ends of the lanes.
And the first step is to load the video and we'll create a new variable video service to thoughts he
will capture.
This is an open CGI glass shoot load videos.
And now we just need to specify the barf videos.
It is the name of the folder with the capital raise lots and effort.
Now we can just check if the video was correct.
It Loaded's if not video is called bents.
If it wasn't possible to load the video, then we can brands an error message for a simple error while
loading their video.
And then we can just type cease but exits to finish the execution of this quote.
Cease is busy boards that we made in the last lecture.
We can just run this code to perform the first test.
We can see here the name of the trackers.
We can also puts this to Brent's comments.
For example, if we change the name here to an invalid name, see that we have this message error while
loading the video.
If this message is not shows, it means that the video was correctly loaded.
Now we need to get the first frame of the video to select the object.
One should track and we'll create two new variables.
OK.
And frame.
The key variable will indicate if we could load the first frame of the video.
On the other hand, the frame variable will start the first frame of the video.
Now we can type video that reads it will read the first frame.
We can also type here, if not, OK.
If we could then load the first frame of the video we can breathe again and error message error while
loading the frame.
And then we can just type CS dot exits.
We can bring into this variable here.
OK, it will return through our foes through if we could get to the first frame and false if there is
one error while loading the frame.
Let's run this code.
See, that's true was returned here, so it means that we would load the first frame of the video.
Now we will find another variable beat box, which means bounding box.
This variable will start the positions of the object in the first frame and choose select the objects
and open C v function, which is select right, and we will send here the first frame ROI means region
of interest.
Now we can run this code again.
See, that's a new window was opened here with the first frame of the video.
The first position and we can see some messages here.
Select array and then bra's space are in there, but you can.
So this selection by pressing see button if you want to count so we can just type lathers, see, we
can see that the process was finished.
Let's run this code again.
Now we can select the object.
For example, we can just draw the balding box in order to select the object one should track in the
first frame.
This is very important when working with tracking algorithms that when you have a video first you need
to select the object in the first frame.
If you click outside the building blocks, you can select and other objects and you.
Fear this selection we can grass space are in there, for example, how will grass in my keyboard's
space see that the process has finished?
Because actually this code is only selecting the object.
We are not tracking the objects yet, and we can also prints this variable bee box.
Let's run again.
Now we'll select the runner press and through see here that some positions were returned.
The first is the x axis.
This once the y axis.
It means the coordinates of the balding box.
And here we have this size of the balding box.
Let's run this code again.
For example, if I click in this part here at the beginning of the image, let's select this region
here.
Press Enter.
See, that was usual.
X is big cell number four, and position way is peak cell number three.
It's at the beginning of the image and see here that these order values are lower than the other ones
because we have a smaller building blocks.
Let's run this code again and select almost the whole we might.
Here we have this big building blocks.
They can look at the positions x and y axis.
And this is this size of the building blocks, the width and the hiph.
So E shortens this variable here where we start the position of the object.
Once should track.
Now we can recreate the OK variable.
Let's go detractor dots in it and we will send here the frame.
This is the first frame of the video and also the beep box variable.
Now we are initializing the algorithm.
Take a look here.
That's the tracker that we are going to use is number six, which is C s r d.
We can change to boasting which was the first one.
You will learn the initial.
So now we will create a boost, the objects.
We will use this algorithm to track the objects.
So in this part, the here we are, initializing the boost the algorithm and we need to send the first
frame and also the position of the object we once should track.
We can prints, OK, here, let's run.
This code selects the runner breasts.
And third, we have here the information about the building blocks, and this message through indicates
that the tracker was successfully initialized.
Finally, we will define and order variable colors equals let's call the function we last as before
ends.
We will generate random numbers between zero and two hundred and fifty five.
Rann's ends zero, two hundred and fifty five.
And finally, Rann's ends zero two hundred and fifty five.
Let's sprints this new variable koala's.
Run this code again.
We need to select.
The objects see here that we have these values, which will be used to define the color of the building
blocks as we are using a random function every time we run, this code will have a different result.
See that these values are different from the others.
And we are defining three values because the pixels of the images are composed of three channels one
channel for the color reds, one channel for technology and one channel for the color bee.
This is the R.G. be for months just to better understand.
We can use these three values in this RGV calculator.
For example, we can type seven.
Then the first number that was generated in January, our one hundred and five in Channel G and one
hundred and sixty five in Channel B, we can see this color here that was randomly generated.
This is the RG before months, however, open civvy works in the formats.
BGR the first channel is blue.
This section is G and the third channel is our.
So to get the call or that two will be generated.
Considering these numbers, we need to change the order of the values.
For example, R is one hundred and sixty five G is one hundred and five, and B is seventeen.
We have these squalor here, so these numbers will create a brown bounding box and we are going to define
these random colors because in next lectures, we are going to implement Moki tracking so we can track
more than one object in a single video, and each one of them will have a different color.
And in the next lecture, we are going to finish this single tracking implementation and we will also
see the results.
See you there.