Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to finish the implementation of single track.
Just a reminder that in the last lectures, we created this code to select the algorithm we are going
to use.
Then we defines the bounding box or the beat box variable, which is responsible for selecting the objects
that one should track, which is in the first frame of the video.
Now we need to go through each one of the frames of the video to continue tracking the objects until
the end.
We can implement a while loop way through a we will redefine the OK variable and also the frame video
that reads Every time we call this read function, we will move on to the next frame of the video.
Take a look here that in this part, we call the read function.
So we have access to the first frame of the video to select the object we once should track.
And when we put this code inside this while loop, we are going through each one of the frames.
First, we get the first frame.
Then this second, the third, the fourth.
And so one let's implement and if statement, if not, OK, if it wasn't possible, short reads the
next frame of the video.
It means that the video has ended so we can just break the zigwheels.com off the wire loop.
This code is used to stop.
Is it usual when the video ends?
In this part of the code, we are initialize the algorithm with the first frame and the first position
of the object.
And every time it reads a new frame, we need to update the location of the building blocks because
in the next frames of the video, the object will be in a different position so we can recreate both
variables.
OK.
And beat box equals tracker thoughts, updates, and we just needs just sans the frame.
And this is not the first frame.
This is this second, the third, the fourth, according to the size of the video.
We use the first frame just to initialize and after the initialization of the algorithm, we need to
update the location.
We can also take a look at this variable.
OK.
And this box?
Let's run this code.
I will select the runner press and there, and we can take a look here at some information we have here.
The first position of the object this is the initial bounding box that we selected using this select
drive function.
And after processing every frame of the video, we are updating the position of the object.
This is the first position X and Y axis.
And this is the second position in this second frame of the video in the third frame of the video.
In the fourth frame of the video and so on.
See that these values here are not changed because they are the size of the building blocks.
And it keeps this same size until the end of the video, and we can take a look here at the message.
It means that the object could be tracked.
And this is the new position of the object, every each one of the frames.
And here is the last position of the object.
We can also brings the OK variable here just to see the value equals false.
Let's run this code again.
Select the runner press.
And there we can see the results here.
But we just.
Needs to put the old key variable after reading the freight.
Let's run again.
Selects the runner.
Press enter, and let's wait until it finishes, processing all the video at the ends, we can see photos
which indicates that we couldn't read any frame any more.
So it means that the algorithm could process all the video and then the break will be executed to stop
the while loop.
Let's put this shoe prints and comments.
And now let's see the results in the video.
If OK.
Equals true, if we could reads and track the objects, we will draw a rectangle to see the results.
Let's create the variables x y w and H e equals in the format of a list less converts.
Shoe ins, ins v. A. We will create these variable v. A. For him.
B. Box.
It means we are accessing this variable, which is composed of the X and Y axis and also the size of
the balding box.
And we are copying each one of the values to each one of these variables.
For example, this first value will be copied to Variable X, this séquence true variable Y, the third
variable W and therefore true variable h.
We can just see these results Breen's X, Y, W and H.
Run this code again.
Let's select the runner and we can see here the results.
We are just copying each one of the values of the building blocks to each one of these variables here
and now we can draw direct Bengal on the image civic dots rectangle.
We can use this open see function.
The first parameter is the frame.
Just a reminder that every time we run this wire loop, we are getting the next, the next and the next
frame.
So we'll put the rectangle in each one of them.
The next parameter is the first position X and Y, which means the initial position of the building
blocks.
The next parameter is the final position of the building blocks, so we can both hear X plus W, which
is the width of the building blocks.
This number here we are just adding this value, plus this value and then y plus h, we are adding these
value plus these are their value here.
Then the X parameter is the colors variable.
As we saw before, we are defining random colors should draw the building blocks.
The next two parameters are related to this size of the building blocks, for example Q and one in some
seconds we're going to perform some tests changing these values if it is not OK.
If we could then update the building blocks with the next position, we will bring a message see visual
words, text frame.
Let's type tracking failure.
When the algorithm was unable to track the objects, the other parameter is the position where we are
going to print the message.
The next one see which new ones Hershey simplex.
This is the type of the ladder this size of the ladder.
The caller in the b r four months zero zero two five five.
And finally, bit thickness off the ladder.
Number two.
And finally, Steve Chu, I am sure you should see the results dragging.
This is the name of the window.
And let's put here this frame, if is true.
But wait here.
This open C differential is used when one should type by specific.
For example, we can type here this symbol.
Zero x f f.
This is the Exodus symbol codes.
If it is equal to twenty seven, then we can break the Z crucial.
This number twenty seven means the ASCII in your keyboard.
So when you press ask, we are going to break the while loop.
So the window will be closed.
Now let's test again.
Run.
Let's select the runner press.
And third, and we can see here, that's the tracking is already working.
Of course, we can see a problem here because we are using the boosting algorithm.
We can press ask in the keyboard's to close the window.
Let's first write with the m i l algorithm, which is index number one.
Run this code again.
Let's select the runner breath and see that every time we run, we have a different caller here because
the callers were defined randomly and see that we have a problem because we selected the Yellow Runner
and the algorithm started tracking this or other runner.
And it happens because these two first algorithms aren't so good, as we saw in the intuition lecturers.
They are the most simplest algorithms to track objects.
So the results once be awards in all scenarios.
Now we can perform some tests using these parameters.
For example, let's change here from choo choo.
Then just just see the results selected the runner and enter.
As you can see, this is this size of the body box.
Let's move again to number two.
And actually, this last parameter, we don't need to specify because it is the type of the line.
For example, if you want a bash line or a solid light, so we don't need to worry about the last parameter.
And the same for this one here we can just raise and we cannot see this message tracking failure because
the body box was generated.
Of course, it wasn't around the objects, but the algorithm could still generate in the building blocks.
We get this message only if we can't open the gate.
The next the location of the object.
In the next lecture, we will perform some other tests and will check when we will get tracking failure.
Finally, we can just put another message on the frame or will copy and paste this code here.
Let's put here the name of the algorithm tracker type the positions 100 and planning, and we can keep
the other parameters.
Now let's run this code again.
Select the runner press, and there we can see here at the top of the video, then name of the algorithm,
so it is nice to see the name of the algorithm in order to check the results and the next lecturer will
perform some tests using all algorithms.
See you there!