Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to perform tests using all algorithms and compare
to results.
First, let's test the boosting algorithms as you learn in the lectures.
This is one of the simplest algorithms.
So the results are not so good.
Let's select the object we want should track breasts and there.
We can see that after only some seconds, the balding box is outside the objects.
In other words, we have that problem.
That's the algorithm loses the object, so it has its good results in this video.
Let's move on to the next algorithm, which is MDL, the one we tested last lecture.
Let's select your runner press and there we can see that it is bad there then boasting it can drag the
object.
But there is a problem, as we saw last lecture that after some frames, it loses the objects and it's
since it is tracking.
That's either runner and lots, the one which selects Let's try c f no to run this code.
Let's select the objects press.
And there we can see that it is a very fast algorithm according to what you learn in the two lectures,
and it has good results badder than boasting and mew in this type of video.
Let's move on to the next one, which is state run this code select the object press and there you can
see this message tracking failure.
And the algorithm couldn't drag the object, it lose the object at the beginning, and you can see here
some other building blocks.
The algorithm has into good results and we can take a look at the of the ear that's massaged.
Tracking failure is shown when the algorithm who then generates the building blocks.
You could see that after some time, some other building blocks are generated at the video, which indicates
that the building blocks was updated but not in the correct location.
In this execution, here we can see that the algorithm wasn't able to generate any building blocks,
so it has terrible results considering this case is 30.
The interesting points about knowing the basic intuition about these algorithms is that you can know
better the way each one behave.
So you'll need to look past them all in order to choose the best one according to your type of application.
Maybe in this scenario, the L.D has terrible results, but in this scenario that you are working,
it may be the best results.
So it's a matter of testing the algorithms.
Now let's move on to the next one, which is median flow.
Let's create the building blocks.
Press and.
We can see that it has in good results again tracking failure and some other bounding boxes were generated
outside the objects.
Let's try to define and order building blocks a smaller building blocks a year press and there.
No improvements in the results using this algorithm.
You can see that it is a fast algorithm.
Now let's move on to the next one, which is the muse algorithm selects the runner press and third.
We couldn't even generate the building blocks in the first frames of the video.
We got the message tracking failure.
Let's try another test.
For example, selecting a smaller building box presenter.
We can see that the body box was generated, but this video is too fast for this algorithm, so we want
to get good results.
And finally, let's perform the test using the best algorithm of all these ones here the c s r d.
Let's select the runner press.
And there you can see that it is a lower algorithm if compares to the others, but we can see that it
can track the drug runner until the end of the video.
Let's change again, should the milk algorithm and the farm at the last test.
I will try to track only the heads of this person here.
Press and there we cannot track.
The algorithm wasn't able and we can see the message tracking failure.
Let's change again.
See as our team.
Let's select the hands.
And in this part two here, even when the heads were very close.
The algorithm could correctly track this heads here, so it has very good results.
And again, when you are developing your own application, I encourage you to test all the algorithms
so you can choose the best one according to the type of application you are developing, and they encourage
you to download author videos and try to pass these algorithms.
And the next lecture, we will implement mode tracking, so we'll be able to select more than one object
should track in this same video.
See you there!