Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to implement multiple tracking, if you remember
last lectures, we implemented this single tracking that the goal is to select only one object.
And in this implementation, we will allow the user to select as many objects he or she wants.
We can press ESC to quit this window and we'll create a new file new by won't file multiple tracking
and I will copy this code of the last example based it here.
And in this lecture will implement some improvements in this part, the EHR.
Remember that we need to put the year the number to get the name of the algorithm.
We will create a new function to be easier.
So the codes will be more organized, less great.
The function grades tracker by name it will receive as a parameter detractor type.
Let's implement and if statement if tracker type, which is this parameter, here we will sand's the
name of the algorithm and we will return the object if it is equal, should tracker types.
Now we are accessing this list here in position zero.
Then let's create the variable tracker switcher dots legacy dots tracker boasting create the same code
we had before Alief tracker type equals.
Let's access the list in position one, which means an AI algorithm Dan tracker will be equal to see
virtual legacy tracker meal create.
I have already typed all this code we can see here the definition of the key CRF DL, the median flow
Morse and C s d, and if we sends an invalid name, we can implement this.
Our statement tracker will be equal to none.
And let's Brian's a message invalid name.
And let's also bring the available list of trackers.
Let's type here available trackers, and let's go through each one of the trackers D and director types.
We are going through this list here to show the name of the available algorithms to the user.
I will brents the which is the name of the tracker.
This far loop is going through each one of the elements of the list and it is copy each one of the names
should the variable.
Then we print it.
And finally, let's return the object returns tracker.
Let's perform some tests.
We brands create tracker by name.
Let's send the here see s our theme.
We can run this code.
We can see that the object was returned.
So it means that this function is returning the tracker correctly.
I will copy and paste this code.
And if we type an invalid name here, for example, see as our date or we'll just put this in commands,
run this code.
See here the message invalid the name and then we can see the available trackers boosting nil, key
CRF and so on.
And at the end, none is returns because we are associating the tracker with an invalid object.
And this is the first part, just an improvement on the code we implemented before the next lecture.
We are going to continue the implementation.
See you there.