Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to continue the implementation of multiple strategy.
Just a reminder that last lecture, we just did some improvements on this single tracking quote.
Now we copied this part here where we are loading the video copy and paste it here.
We can put this brilliance in comments.
We are just loading the video and then we will define new variables.
The first one bit boxes and empty list and colors again, and the lists in this single tracking example,
we have only one building blocks and now we need to select more than one building blocks in the first
frame of the video.
So we are going to start all the bounding boxes and the corresponding colors in these new variables,
how we will define a look way through.
Let's create the big box variable true thoughts select ROI in order to select the region of interest.
Let's Typekit here.
Load the tracker.
It is the name of the window, and we also need to specify the first frame of the video.
Let's create these variables here.
OK?
And frame Hadeel thought rate.
We are accessing this variable here.
We are copying through the frame variable, the first frame of the video.
After selecting the building blocks, we will access the big box is variable dots are bands b box.
We are adding the boarding box to this list here.
We also need to access the colors variable.
And let's define the random numbers in order to have different colors.
Reds ends.
Zero two five five Common Grounds ends zero two five five All My Rands ends zero two five five.
We are generating a different color for each one of the boarding boxes.
Now we need to define the key should be pressed on the keyboards to interrupt the execution of this
while loop after we select all objects that one should track and we will create a new variable.
Key equals C ritual weight Typekit zero.
This parameter zero is expecting a key from the keyboards and we also need this exact decimal codes.
And now we can just check if key equals one one three.
This is the codes for ladder key, which means quid's.
So when we press wits, we will interrupt the execution of the while loop.
Then we can just break the code to be easier fast to this code.
Let's sprints two messages.
Press key should quit and start tracking.
And another print press and your other key should select the next object.
Now, let's run this code.
We have that same in messages so we can open this window.
Let's suppose we want to track this runner with select the him, and then we press Space R and through
to confirm the selection.
Let's press enter.
Now we can see the new messages press key to quit and start tracking and press any other key to select
the next object.
If we press key, see that there is a queue show is interrupt.
So it means we and third this if statement here and the while loop is stopped.
Let's run again.
We'll select the runner.
Press enter.
And now we can press and.
The other, a key to select the next object, you can't press any other ladder, for example, A, B,
C, D, B and so on.
How we press ladder B, we can see the message again, select the ROI and then press space or enter.
I will select these other runner press and third.
Now we can see this message again.
Let's suppose we want to select another object so we can press any other key.
For example, Ladder A, we select the order enter.
And when we finish selecting all the objects one should track, we can press key and then the wire loop
is interrupted to see the bounding boxes.
We can print bit boxes and we can also prints the colors off each one of them.
Let's run again.
I will select the first runner press and there I will type Leader B to select the next runner.
Press and their ladder B or any other key.
Just select other objects.
I will select this one here.
Press Enter.
Then I will press Ladder Q and then we can see the results.
Three bounding boxes with three corresponding our g b colors.
And this is the codes needed to select each one of the objects one should track.
We need three bounding boxes and three different colours.
And in the next lecture, we will finish the implementation.
See you there!