Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to finish the implementation of multiple tracking.
Just a reminder that in the last lecture, we Glickman man did this while loop in order to select the
objects that one should track, we will have, as a result, a list of several bounding boxes with the
corresponding colors.
Now we will create the tracker type variable, which will be the name of the algorithm.
Let's perform this test with CSIRO.
The algorithm, which is one with bad results, and we will create another variable MO team director
equals C ritual and there is this order glass from open circuit, which is mo the track to create.
We can take a look here.
That's before we were creating each one of the algorithms.
And now, as we can have more than one tracker, we can use MO detractor to create.
Now we need to go through the building blocks for big blocks in big boxes.
We are going through this list of these selected objects and we need to add detractors, Mo Detractor
Dots adds.
And let's call our function grades tracker by name and let's send here.
Tracker type, which in this example is the C SRT algorithm.
Let's suppose we select three objects to track each one off than will be tracked using this same algorithm.
And if you want, you can sends different algorithms and lots this same as we are implementing here.
We also needs to send the Here diff frame, which is the first frame of the video in order to initialize
the algorithms.
And also, we will Sand's here, the building blocks.
We are going through each one of the objects and adding them should demo the tracker.
Now we can go through each one of the frames of the video while the video is open when we have the next
frame of the video, which is a cute Discord's.
Let's create the variables OK, key and frame.
Just a reminder again, that this variable here is the first frame of the video that is used only to
select the position of the objects that one should track and decide the variable here.
We will receive each one of the next frames.
Let's Typekit here.
VIDEO Dots grids, if not, OK, if it wasn't possible to redo the next frame, we can break this loop.
Let's recreate.
OK.
And boxes.
Let's go mo detractor dots update.
And let's send the here to frame.
This is exactly the same we had before.
First, we need to initialize the algorithm with the initial positions of the object, and then we just
update, according should the next frames.
Let's create a for loop for AI and new box to variables AI and grading now in enumerate boxes.
This for a loop is going through each one of the boxes because if we select three objects to track,
we will have three boarding boxes as a result.
And now we need to go through each one of these update its bounding boxes in order to draw the rectangle,
and the enumerate function is used to give indexes for the boxes.
For example, in the first is a crucial of the for a loop.
We will get the here, the first building blocks and the.
Has index zero, then we will have this second bounding box with index one.
This third balding box with index chew, will we use the eye variable to axis this order variable here
to get the colors of each balding box?
Now we can create x y w h equals the same code we have implemented before.
We are going through each one of the bounding boxes and loads, each one of the values in each one of
these variables here for V in new box.
Now we can draw a rectangle signature rectangle.
The first parameter is the frame.
The initial position of the building blocks, the final position X plus w y plus h.
And now we are going to use the colors variable and we will sans variable.
I hear the last barometer is the size of the balding box, which will be equal to two after the last
part signature.
I am show less Typekit here.
The title of the window motif tracker the frame and if ritual weight key one in zero x f f equals twenty
seven, which is the ASC key.
So when you press this key in your keyboard, the Z usual will be interrupts.
We just break the look.
Now let's run this gold and perform the tests.
I will select the first runner press and there now we can see this message here, presenting either
a key to select the next object.
You can press any other key.
For example, Ladder B, I will select desired runner press and there then we can select another one,
presenting any other key, and then we'll select the last one here.
Press enter.
And now we can rescue weights and start tracking.
We can see that's when it was returns module Civic, which has no attributes mode detractor creates
because we need to access this other package called legacy.
Let's run again and I will select the runners this séquence one and the third one presenter and Q.
And finally, we can see the results using C as our the algorithm.
We can see that's the algorithm is performing well.
It's possible to track the three objects at the same time.
Let's wait until the end of the race.
As you can see, it is quite is low because we are executing the algorithms using three objects.
And this is how you can perform multiple tracking using open Siri.
See you in the next lecture.