Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to implement the equal third algorithm using
open CV in less lectures.
We can see that we implement it all or there's algorithms and it's missing third.
And the way we implement in a different file, as you can see here, because there is a small difference
on the implementation.
As you learned in the intuition lectures, this algorithm uses convolutional neural networks to perform
tracking.
So we need to load some additional files and we'll click here based.
See, that's true.
Files will be copied here.
Go Third Dot Pro to the X and go third Dot Fair Model.
You can get both files in the course materials.
Now we are going to implement an if statement just to make sure these files are in this same folder
as the source code here.
If not all s got fast is file.
Now we can by the name of the file go.
Those dots got Sam Wardle and in case you don't know, Gotham model is a deep learning framework.
So the neural network was strains using these framework.
This file contains the weights of the neural network, and these are their file here.
We can open it.
It has the data about the neural network.
For example, we can see here the convolutional layers.
Don't worry about understanding the structure of the neural network because this is not the goal of
the course.
You just need to load both files in order to work with this algorithm and all s there is file.
This function is used to check if the file exists in the folder.
Now let's type go through to the X state.
If we can't loads both files, let's bring the message.
Error loading the network files and then we can just type C's exits to enter up the execution.
We can run this file.
No error was returned because both of them are here in this same folder as this service code.
We can't write.
Should change the name here.
Run this code again.
Now we get the error message error loading the network files.
Now let's create the tracker, which will be equal.
True spiritual legacy the same code we implement as before Tracker Go.
Third, create.
Now we can run this code.
See that one error was returns because for the user specific algorithm, we don't need to use the legacy
package.
We can just keep C ritual tracker third.
Great.
Let's run it again.
See, that's no error was returned.
And from now, we can use exactly the same code we implemented before.
The only difference between this algorithm and the others is that you need both files here, and we
will just paste this code here.
It is this same we implement as before.
First, we load the video, then we get the first frame.
We have the definition of that right.
Dredging of interest are, in other words, the object that we want should track.
We initialize the algorithm, sending the first frame and also the building blocks of the first position
of the object.
Here we have the definition of the random caller and inside the while loop, we have this same code
as before we load the next frame of the video.
If we cannot load the next frame so we break, this is a crucial of the way you look.
We update the building blocks, if we can.
They did then we just draw that rectangle.
If we cannot update, we have the tracking failure message.
We put the text with the name of the algorithm in the top part of the video.
And finally, we just showed the results.
This code is exactly the same for the other algorithms.
Now let's run the algorithm, select the object one should track.
And as you can see, we don't have good results using go turn with open Siri because as you learn in
the intuition lectures, you need to be sure about the objects that this algorithm was trained as a
wave because as you learned, it was trained using off-line learning.
So datasets with thousands of videos was used to train the algorithm, so you need to make sure that
the objects you want should track are in these datasets.
That's the algorithm was trained.
Otherwise, you want to get good results, and in the next lecture, we will continue the implementations.
See you there.