Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to implement a detection algorithm and right
after we will combine the tracking algorithm with detection algorithm.
And just to better understand what we are going to implement, we will run this single tracking file.
Let's choose here the most algorithm.
Let's run these codes.
Select the object.
We ones should drag press and there.
And you will see that after some time, the boarding box loses the objects.
We can run this code again.
Let's select these other runner here.
Only the top part of the body.
We can see that after some time, the building blocks is far from the object.
And when this situation happens, we can run detection algorithm to try to get the object again because
if you is still running the tracking algorithm, probably you want to get good results.
Since the algorithm is losing the object so we can combine both techniques when the tracking algorithm
loses the object, we will run a detection algorithm in order to get the object again.
And in this first lecture, we will implement a detection algorithm and then we will combine both.
We will create a new Python file based detection.
Let's import to the libraries part switcher or been Sivy, and we will create the image variable spiritual.
I am riads and let's create a new folder here directory.
I will call images.
I will paste the best image here.
You can get this image in the course.
Materials, people, dots, jpg.
We can open this much.
We can see a lot of people here and they go, Wow, is should that back to the full body of each one
of them?
In this example about the combination of both algorithms, we are not going to use the same video as
before.
We will use a different one.
Now we can just type here the name of the image before BALF image is God's people.
JPG.
I will based a new folder here, which is the Cascade folder, and we can see here some x m l files.
For example, Full-Body Cascades, I higher cascade from dollface, lower body and upper body.
These are files that were already drained in order to detect the parts of the body of people.
For example, only the upper bounds the part of the heads, the lower bounds, the part of the legs.
Only deferral now face the eyes and the full body.
And this is the most common technique in opacity to detect objects.
And these files are already trained to detect these parts of the body, and you don't need to worry
about how they were generated.
Since this is not the goal of the course, we are going to use, the full body file should detect the
people here.
Now we need to create our detector, which will be equal to see virtual cascades classifier and we just
need to send it here.
The name of the file cascades, the directory and full body dot x m l.
We can just run this code just to make sure no error was returns.
Then we can convert the image to Grayscale because when working with Cascade the classifier, this opens
technique.
It is recommended to convert this image to Grayscale so we can create another variable in which gray
equals C, which you see fit the color.
Let's send the original image and color b g are too great to see the results we can tie.
I am sure let's put it the name of the window people.
An image great Etienne's let's start waits key parameter zero.
It demands that the window will be waiting until we press a key.
Let's run these codes.
We can see this window here if we don't type C V to weight key.
We want to be able to see this great.
Chaos in which we can type and key and then the window will be closed.
Now we can use our detector to detect the full body of the people.
Let's create the detection variable detector and to detect objects we can call.
This function detects multi scale and we just need to choose sans émigré.
We can't bring the results, brilliant detections we can put.
These two lines comments.
Let's run this quote again.
See, that's some bounding boxes were returns with the position off where the full body of the people
were detected.
We can also Brandt's length detections just see how many objects were detected.
The result is nine.
Let's open the much better.
One two three four five six seven eight nine people here, so it seems that the algorithm is able to
detect all people.
Now we can draw the bounding box in the image.
Just a reminder that's the actual first values are related to the position, the x axis and the y axis
where the object was found in the image.
While the last two values are the width and the height of the body box that was detected.
Now we can implements a far loop for x y width and height in detections.
We can greens all these variables just to see the results outputs these commands.
Let's run the code, see that we are going through each one of the bounding boxes and just copy the
values to each one of the variables.
Now we can draw the rectangle CV two dots rectangle, the first parameter, the image see that we are
drawing the rectangle in the original image, in the ARG image, and we are using the grayscale image
just to run the algorithm.
The second parameter is the initial blinds.
The third parameter is the and points of the building blocks, and we put the same values as here.
The next one is the color zero, two, five, five and zero, and the last one is this size of the building
blocks.
Now we can remove the command here to see the results, and we also need to show the image, see which
I am sure detections.
And here we are going to sans the image.
It's important to emphasize that we are drawing the bounding box on the original image and after visualizing
the image, we can destroy all windows to release the memory.
Let's run again.
We can open the window.
We can see some points here, which is the initial point of the building blocks of each one of the people.
This is the X and y axis, but we need to draw the building blocks, so we just needs to add to the
values x plus with f y plus age.
Now let's run again.
Open the window and we can see the results.
The algorithm was able to draw the building blocks for each one of the people.
We just have some problem here.
That's only the lag was detected.
And if you want to improve the results, you can check the documentation of this function detect multiscale
in order to see more parameters.
It's not the goal of this lecture to go into these details.
The goal is just to show you how you can use a detection algorithm, and in the next lecture, we are
going to combine the detection algorithm with the tracking algorithm.
See you there!