Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to start the implementation of the combination
of the tracking algorithm with the detection algorithm.
Just a reminder that last lecture you understood how to use the higher Cascada detector to detect the
full body of people.
Now let's create a new file by file.
The name of this file will be detection tracking.
Let's import the library's important spiritual import sis am from random import rant ins.
Now let's create the tracker equals spiritual legacy, and we use Tracker C as our theme.
You can use the one you want.
We are going to use SRT because, as we saw before, it too has the best results.
Now we can go to this single tracking and now we we'll just copy this code here to load the video based
IDs.
And let's paste the new video that we are going to use.
Click here on based walking.
The name of the file and you can get this video in the class materials.
Here is the video that we are going to use in this case study.
We can see a lot of people walking on this street, and the goal is just to select a specific person
and track the person until the end of the video.
And if we use a tracking algorithm after some frames the tracking algorithm, we will lose the object
and then we are going to use the detection algorithm to try to get to the object again.
Then we can restart the tracking algorithm.
Let's just change the name here walking.
But, Azi, let's run these quotes.
No, it was returns.
So the video was loaded correctly.
And also, we could get the first frame of the video.
Now we will create the cascaded detector, which will be equal.
See Richard Gasquet classifier and let's sand to hear the full path of the file full body Dodd's x m
l.
As you saw in the video, we have the full body of people so we can use this file here.
If you are working with eye tracking or only tracking the from tho face of people, you can use these
or other cascade files and we will create a new function that detects it wont receive any parameter.
Let's see implements a while while true.
OK.
And Frame Hadeel Dot reads.
See here that we are reading the next frame of the video.
Now we will get the frame, which is the first image.
And let's go over to Grayscale as you learn in the last lecture to work with the Cascade classifier,
it is recommended to convert the IAG B image short grayscale image.
We will implement a similar code we implement as before severity call the frame signature color b g
r sugary.
After we convert, we can get the detections equals cascades and let's go detect multi scale and let's
send it here.
The grayscale image.
Now we need to go through the building blocks exactly the same with the ID here.
See that we first get the detections and then we need to go through.
Each one of the detections are the building blocks for x y.
We live in the hive in detections.
I will draw direct dango frame.
Take a look here that we are covered in the image true grayscale.
We are detecting the full body in degrees Q image, but we are going to show the results in the our
G.B. image.
Let's split here.
The first point?
The last point X blurs with f y B+ hiph the color of the boarding box.
Zero zero two five five.
And this size?
Sure, let's show the results.
C Ritual.
I am show detection, and let's put the frame here.
After that, we can visualize the results spiritual weight here and after we press a key, let's destroy
all windows to release the memory.
Now we can perform the first tests using this function.
Let's call it detects and we'll run these codes.
We can take a look at some images.
This is the second frame of the video since we have here.
This code ETRADE's the first frame and the higher Cascades wasn't able to detect the full body in this
frame.
We can press any key, then we move on to the next frame of the video.
The algorithm is detecting this rock here as if it were a person, but now we can see that the algorithm
could detect the full body of this person.
Here we can move on to the next frames.
We can see that's the algorithm can detect other people and you can press and.
Are you can press any other key on your keyboard?
And you can see that's the algorithm is detecting the full body of people.
Of course, there are some errors here, but it once be a problem for our case study.
I will click this button here to stop this crucial, and they go of this function is to detect the first
person who appears in the first frame of the video, as we can see here in this single tracking when
we run this code.
We need to select the building blocks in order to start tracking them when we press anther.
The algorithm starts is incubating birds in this other case is third that we are implementing.
The goal is to select the first burst so that the algorithm could detect.
So we are not going to use this function here.
This will act right because when you use this function, a window will appear and you need to select
the object by yourself.
But in these other cases, they will automatically select the first body that appears in the video.
And in order to do that, we can implement an if statement.
If X greater than zero.
If a detection was found, then we can just sprints higher cascades detection and then we can return
the building blocks x y.
We live and hiph.
The difference is that a single tracking, we select the object and we have here the building blocks
according to our selection.
Now we will return the building blocks according to the first frame of the video, or in other words,
according should the first object that was detected.
Now we can create the building blocks here, and then we can just sprints the beat box.
Let's run this code.
We can click here, stop and rerun.
See that we have the detection, hard cascaded detection, and we have only the first building blocks.
This is the X and Y positions.
And here we can see this size of the object that was detected, and in the next lecture, we will initialize
our tracker.
According to these body blocks here and then we combine both algorithms, the detection algorithms and
the tracking algorithm.
See you there.