Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to finish the combination of a detection algorithm
with a tracking algorithm.
Just a reminder that last lecture we implemented mandates this function that we will reads the first
frame of the video and then we will get to the balding box of a person when we call this function.
We copy to this variable the return of the function with the position of the body box.
And now we are going to go through each one of the frames of the videos in order to run this tracking
algorithm.
The code will be quite similar to the one we implemented before, while drew lock and frame video Dot
reads Create the next frame of the video.
If not, OK, then we finish the execution of the while loop if there is no frame treats when we reach
the ends of the video.
Now that's great again.
The OK variable and the balding box equals Dracula dots update and let's sans didn't next frame.
We can see here that we defined detractor the C s R D algorithm, and in this line of code, we are
updating the location r the position of the body box.
Just a reminder that we are using these function together to the object instead of using this select
right function.
The algorithm itself will select the object to track if OK, if we would update the building blocks,
let's create X and Y variable w h equals int z.
Let's go through each one of the values of the building blocks for a V in B box.
Now we can draw direct dango signature rectangle frame position X and Y X Plus W Y plus h.
Let's put to hear the callers.
What we need is to define this variable.
We will use random crawlers.
Let's just paste this code here.
We can put this building blocks in commands, and we also needs to initialize the tracker tracker dots
in it.
Let's sans the first frame and also the building blocks the initial position that will be got from these
function detect to here.
If we are not able to track the objects we can grants that messaging, tracking failure and we are going
to treat Blue Man some additional codes in this part here.
But first, let's just try how the tracking is working, so it sure I am.
So let's put here the name of the window tracking and frame.
Let's create the key variable to weight key parameter when the window waits for a special key.
And then if key equals twenty seven, which means they ask key, then we just break it while loop to
close the window.
Here we just delete this symbol.
We can run this code.
There is one error object has no attribute ins because here it's missing leather eye tracker dots in
it.
Let's perform the first test.
Run this code.
Let's open the window.
See that the rock was detected by the cascade.
You can see that it is open.
They think the building blocks.
It means that tracking is working correctly.
However, as this rock is not moving, we cannot see the.
AIDS and we can make some improvements to not detect this rock as it were up first, so we can set up
parameters to detect smoke the scale.
Let's Typekit here means size, which is the mean size of the object.
Let's type here 60 by 60.
This is the minimal size of an object should be detected as this size of the rock is lower than this
value than we will detect another object.
Let's run the detector again.
We can take a look at that, too.
Now we can detect the person, but after some time we can see that we lose the building blocks.
And when it to happen, we will run the detection algorithm again to choose another person in order
to continue tracking.
We will implement this part in this house estate demand if it is not okay to continue tracking the object.
We will send this message tracking failure and then the other message we will execute the higher cascades
detector and now we will recreate the building blocks, just calling our detect function.
We will call this function.
It will reads the next frame of the video and we will return to the position of the full body of a person
in order to restart the detector.
Now we can recreate our director, director Sylvia Chu, Butt's legacy tracker.
I will choose another one, for example.
Tracker was great.
You could also use C s r d r any one you want in this code.
We are.
Is it?
You would think short tracking algorithms at the beginning of this is crucial.
We are using C s r d, and when we have a tracking failure, we will use the most algorithm and then
we need to initialize tracker dots in its frame and B box.
We are initializing the tracking algorithm again, according to the new building blocks, before executing
the first test.
Let's remove this common to here just to show the first object that was detected.
Run detection tracking and here we can take a look at the first objects in the first frame of the video,
and then we can see that the algorithm started tracking.
But see, that's it's a has lose the object.
But we don't have here that failure message because the bounding box is being generated.
Of course, it is not correct.
It is not tracking any objects, but we are not executing this part of the code here, and it happens
because of the size of the building blocks.
As we can see here again.
The building blocks is very big and the person is not so big as the building blocks.
We can also take a look at our fast detection file.
Let's run it and we can see that the building blocks are also big.
It means that we are sending to the tracking algorithm.
All this information about the backgrounds.
So the tracking algorithm will have some difficulties in tracking the objects since the building blocks
is too big and it is a problem of these file here.
The full body x m l so it is not so accurate to detect the full body of people.
It would be bad there if the building blocks was smaller around the object and not so big.
With this, information about the background and the tracking algorithms will use the information about
the background to track the objects.
Let's run this code again.
We can see here the size of the building blocks, see that we have this background information here
that it is part of the object, as we can see here, because the bounding box is considering the big
skills about the person and also the pixels about the background.
So it would be bad if we had a more accurate cascade.
It should detect full body of people to solve this problem.
We can implemented this code in a different way instead of using the detect function in the first frame.
We can use differential.
We were using before switcher, but select right and let's send differing inputs desired through line
commands.
Now we will be able to see this message and now we'll put all this part commands just to see if we will
get this tracking failure message.
Let's run this code again.
Now we need to select the object one should track before we had a big building blocks and now we can
create a building blocks according to the size of the person.
Less press enter.
See here.
That's the tracking has already started, and let's wait until we see the mass such tracking failure.
See, that's the algorithm, lose the object.
Now we have this message, Trekkie failure and the tracking algorithm is not being executed anymore
because there was this failure and we could then update the building blocks.
So now we can run this code in order to call the function, should detect the object.
Let's remove the comments.
Let's run the codes again.
The first step is to select the object we want should track.
Let's run it.
And here we can see the video.
So the algorithm is called the new tracking the objects.
And see here that only one it was returns.
Anything happens because they changed the here.
Should this see s our D algorithm?
So we are initializing with C s r d, and when we have a tracking failure error, we are executing again.
We can try now with the Muise algorithm, as we had before.
Let's run this code again.
I'll we'll select the first object we want should track the goal.
We should track people.
Let's run this code.
We can see the video here, the right select through with the first frame.
Now, let's wait until the algorithm returns.
A tracking failure at this part here.
This is the new object.
It was executed once.
Similar to the order algorithm and you can test with other algorithms.
We'll run this code again and we will select a bigger bounding box, less right to run again.
And the results will depends on this first building blocks, of course, after we have a tracking failure,
or we will have a big building blocks because we are using the hard cascade.
Here that we have this big building blocks.
And again, only one agent was returned.
Let's try again, and now we'll select this other person here.
Press, enter and let's see the results.
One, a horror was returned, he heard this same as before and after the algorithm finishes the execution.
This is how you can combine both algorithms when you have a tracking failure.
You can run the detection algorithm again.
As I said before this cascade here, full body is generating quite big, balding boxes.
It would be more interesting, and the results would be bad if we had the building blocks at the same
size of the objects and in the next lectures we will moving to more advanced tracking algorithms.
See you there!