Hello and welcome to this lecture, where you are going to learn the basic intuition about the Meaning
Shift algorithm, which uses space analysis to find the maximum off adding city function.
They both texts here are the main concepts of the algorithm.
And now let's understand how it basically works.
It determines the weight of nearby points are big cells based on average calculation using crawlers.
Let's suppose that in this animation, there are four big cells one, two, three and four, and you
select these white peaks.
So here's a Two-track.
So the algorithm will move towards these white peaks.
So as you can see, the pixels are moved until they reach this area here where you once should track.
This is the thing, said the function when the number of peak cells is greater.
It is basically an approximation of the peak cells, according to the features of the initial object.
This other image shows another example where you can see the arrow moving towards these white bar here,
which might be what one should track.
So this is the density function.
There is another representation of the algorithm that are a set of points on the left side, and some
windows are circles here.
These three points, the algorithm needs to move.
These windows are circles should these areas here where I am pointing the mouse.
The algorithm will approximate this Reds peak sales trapeze image.
In other words, we are going to move to the area of maximal pixel density where there are more pixels
than in other parts of the image.
It will be moved should these red bars at the top where the density is higher.
Below we have the representation with these three bars and this is the biggest because there are more
pixels here.
Let's count, for example, one two three four five six seven pixels, so the bar is higher than the
others in this one one two three four five six pixels.
So the bar is smaller than this one here.
And finally, in this point here, there are only one big so.
So the bar is is smaller than the others.
So this is the density function that counts the number of pixels in each one of these windows here.
The size of the bars indicates the density, as you can read here.
The data point density The goal is to bring these points closer to these image, which is equivalent
should these one above and the ladders beat the f stand for probability density function, which is
the mathematical calculation used in mean shift.
We can consider this image here as the current frame of the video and this image here as the next frame,
a confidence map based on probabilities will be created to approximate the frames so that the algorithm
can identify where the target object is.
Larger bars here are related to greater probabilities, while smaller bars indicate less probability
of the object being in this position here.
In short, the object one should track is in this central part.
Where did things sit?
The R number of pixels cells is greater.
This or other animation shows how the upper.
Summation works that are more pixels in the center.
And the algorithm goes here where the object is located.
This is the basic intuition about missing shift and in the next lecture where we start the implementations.
See you there!