Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to start the implementation of the mean shift
algorithm.
We are back to the bike sharing project.
Let's create a new bike file.
The name of this file will be mission shift.
Let's see boards the libraries in Part C ritual and the we will install another library.
We can click here and there are, you know, and let's type be installed.
I am or those breaths.
And there we can see here.
That's the installation was successfully done.
And this is a library to work with videos in Python.
We will use it in some sections.
Now we can import a class from this new library from I am would use that video import video stream in
this case study.
We are not going to load a video from this folder here, as we did before.
We will load the videos from the web cam.
Now we can create the capture variable video history in this new class that we have just part.
It's the first parameter is this service which will be equal to zero, which means the web can in case
you have more cameras installed on your computer.
The webcam will be camera zero and the other cameras will be camera one, camera two, camera three
and so one.
And now we are going to start capturing the images from the webcam.
How will we import and larger library here in time?
And let's type here?
I thought this is a Leap One, which means that we are going to wait one seconds before we start capturing
the images from the webcam.
And we need these quotes because when we are capturing videos from the webcam, it needs some seconds
in order to adapt to the environment.
For example, maybe you have already seen that when you turn on the webcam.
It takes one or two seconds to adapt to the light conditions.
For example, even if you were in a light environment when you open the webcam in the first Milicic
once the image will be quite dark because the webcam is adapting to the environment.
So we are going to use these codes to wait one sec once to give time.
Should the webcam adapts, should the lightning conditions and we are going to select the object was
should track after this process.
In short, we are giving one seconds to the webcam, adapts to the light and in conditions of the environment.
Now we can recreate the cap variable civic through video capture.
Again, we will put zero, which means that we are getting the images from the webcam.
If you remember the order lecturers here, we typed the path of the video, so the code is the same.
Three video files are to get the video from the webcam.
I will create new variables or OK and frame equals.
Yep, that reads.
To get the first frame of the video are the first frame when the webcam is initialized.
Just a reminder that this variable.
OK will tell was if the connection was made successfully.
We can just prints OK just to see if we can get the images from the webcam.
Let's run this code.
We can see this message here.
It means we could get the video from the webcam now will create the beatbox variable civic through dots.
Select Right.
We are going to select the object from the webcam.
Will put the heater the first frame of the video after selecting the building blocks.
Let's create x y width and the hive variables equals B box.
We can create another variable and we call it as tracking window, which is the object which one should
track, and it will be equal to each one of these variables here.
Let's sprints the track window just to see the results.
Now we can run this code.
We can see the first frame of the video.
I am holding up ban and the goal will be to track this span.
We can select a small bounding box here just with this part.
And after pressing space or enter, we can see that we have the same messages as before we get.
As a result, the building blocks of the initial object that we want should track.
We can see here Position X, Position Y and this size of the building blocks just that small part of
the BAM.
Now we need to create a new image which will be equal to all these part of the image.
Only the objects are the part of the band I selected before the object one should track.
So we can create a new variable called ROI, which means region of interest and we can access our frame.
This is the initial frame that was rad.
The here and now we can type the following codes Y and feel y plus h.
This is the initial position of the image.
X x plus w.
We are using these two variables here to get the initial points of the building blocks, and these are
their points here which are related to this size of the object we select.
This sugar adds only that's part of the image.
We can visualize the results, see which I am sure the title of the window, right?
And let's put here the new variable and see which to weight.
Kim No.
Zero.
The window will be opened until we press a key on the keyboard.
Now, let's run this code again.
I will select the building blocks a small one here.
Press enter.
And we can see this order window here with just off this part of the image that I have just selected.
We first need to get to this initial part in order to sans should the algorithm, so it will track only
this part of the ban.
And this is the first part of the implementation where we give time to the webcam to adapt.
Should the lightning conditions with select, the object we want should drag using select drive from
open sivy and then we get only the part of the image that we should track.
And in the next lecture, we will continue the implementation.
See you there!