Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to continue the implementation of the May shift
tracking algorithm.
Just to recap, we can run this code.
Then we can get the building blocks, for example, we can select the pen press and there and we can
see here that Roy Director Dhiraj of interest.
This is the object we once should track, which is the track window.
And now we need to perform some brass see on this Roy image.
We'll put these two lines in commands.
And as you know, this image is in the RGV for months.
Of course, in open CV, the order of the channels are different.
So we have beat our image and we need to convert these our r.b.g.
Our image Chuan Lauder for months, which is the H s v.
It is another caller representation or another caller space.
And if you want to know more details about the caller ID spaces, you can follow these first link here,
where you can find more information about caller spaces.
For example, they are used according to the available light in the environment, the way the objects
in this scene that reflect light, the way the light reacts with an animal's eyes and the way received
light is processed.
Different color spaces are used, according should these four features here, and we can take a look
at the art be quality space, which is the one used in computers and it is considered the default color
space.
And we can take a look at the age s v color space and it stands off.
Have the rads, green and blue channel.
We have the rule.
This saturation and the value as the mean shift algorithm is based on all laws.
We need to convert the image from the our g b format should the H s V formats, because this is how
mean shift algorithm was implemented so we can create a new variable age s hit ROI equals spiritual
celebrity.
Let's send here the right or the object.
One should drag city to caller Kuala BGR chew h.
S V, and just to compare the results of each one of the corollaries spaces, we can show the window
civic.
Sure, i m show let's type here, right h s v h s here, right?
See feature, but wait here, let's run this code again.
And so it will be easier to see the difference between the actual color spaces.
We can select the right again, let's press and there and now we can see the difference between the
original one and the color changed from our GP to HSV.
We can delete this comment here.
Let's run again.
Let's select the part of the ban again.
Press enter.
Now we can see both spaces.
The original one, the IGB and the same image converted to HSV.
We can put this line in the comments and this is the first pre-processing step we need to convert the
object from our GP to HSV.
Then we will need to perform these calculations here to approximate the number of big cells should these
areas are.
Should these bars, for example?
This is the biggest one because there are more big cells in this window here.
This is this sac big guests, because that our last big cells than this one here.
And then we need to approximate these bars should then next frame of the video in order to keep tracking
the object.
We need to compare the previous frame with the next frame.
And the next step now is to generate these bars and the bars are called histogram.
And you can follow this link to know more details.
We can take a look at the theory here.
The Instagram is a graph are blots, which gives you an overall idea about the things that the distribution
of an image.
For example, we are going to count the number of big cells, according to the.
For example, see, that's in this part of the image.
We can see the brown color and the number of brown big cells are higher than the number of these color
here near this see.
So the bar regarding the brown color is bigger than the bar.
Regarding these other color, because the number of brown pigs cells are greater than the number of
these white pig.
So here and we can also take a look at this point here, which is a different color.
But as this small thing is far from the camera, the color is quite a difference.
And then the number of big cells belonging to this squalor is is smaller than the number of big cells
belonging to this or other brown color.
So basically, the histogram will give us the number of peak cells belonging to each one of the different
colors of the image.
Going back to these is light.
Here we can consider these points here as the brown color.
These are other points here as these are either called or here.
And finally, decide they're part two here as these white collar.
So basically, in order to perform the calculations, the makeshift algorithm will use the histogram
with the number of pixels off each one of the colors of the image.
So then we can compare these histograms with the histograms of the next frame of the video.
If the algorithm can find similarities between both histograms, it means that it can keep tracking
the object.
This is how Ming Shift finds similarity between the courants and the max frame of the video.
It will compare the histograms.
Here, you can find the open civil codes to get the histogram of the image, and now we are going to
implement it.
Let's go back to the bicarb project and we'll create another variable right highest civic hue dots,
calc history and the first parameter is h se v at right.
We are going to get the histogram regarding the right converted to H.
S V Colors space.
The next parameter is the number of.
Channels, we are going to use only one channel.
If you want to know more details about the parameters, you can check this link here.
For example, if the input image is in grayscale, the value is zero.
So we are going to get the histogram.
Considering our grayscale image, then the X parameter is the mask image and we need you sat as no one
to find the histogram of full image.
And as we need to get the histogram of the ROI, we need you.
None.
Here we would use this barometer.
If we want to find the histogram of a particular region of the image, then the X parameter is the least
size.
These represent the beam counts, which is the number of bars that will be generated or the number of
ether votes.
For example, in this image, there are about 20 bars, so that barometer would be equal to 20.
We can type one hundred and eighty, which is the number of bars that will be generated or the number
of colour intervals, and in the documentation ofmy shift algorithm.
It is recommended to use this value in the last parameter, our order ranges.
For example, the default value from zero to 200 and 55, which is the IGB interval.
And as we are working with age s v, the range will be from zero to one hundred and eighty.
So now we have the histogram of the array and we can visualize a graph like this.
One here should show the number of pixels according to each one of the callers should do that.
We are going to use another library.
I will click here and there.
Now let's install maths blots live, which is the default library to generate graphs in Python.
We can see that the installation was done successfully.
Now we can import this library import Matt blot lib by brought s BLT, and we can use Matt Blot Lib
to generate the histogram.
Lets type he's ROI and I will define the same parameters.
Then we can show the graph switcher weight gain zero.
Let's run this code.
And when it was returned here, because these right variable is an image, so it is in the matrix formats
and we need to convert enough vector formats only one dimension to generate the histogram.
Let's try to run this code again.
The first step is just select the right press and through.
And we can see the result here, which is quite similar to that one in open civil documentation.
We can see here the total amount of big cells regarding each one of the callers.
Most of the values are in the range from 75 to 175, which are related to the yellow collar, according
to the ban.
In short, these are the most frequent callers and take a look here that we are generating.
The histogram using the original image so it is easier to see the results.
Now we can put these codes in comments.
We are not going to visualize that this graph anymore.
It was used just to see the results and the last step of this lecturer.
We will recreate high.
His equal spiritual dots normalize as we know the values are in the range from zero to 255.
And we need to convert them into range from zero to one.
So it will be faster to process is the algorithm.
We are going to normalize the image.
We are going to stand here the high wrist again, the right history, the original interval zero, two
hundred and fifty five spiritual ma'am mean max.
This option will convert the values of the pixels in the range from zero to one, and then the next
and last lecture we are going to finally visualize the results.
See you there!