Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to finish the implementation of the mean shift
algorithm, as you could see, this is a quite more complex algorithm if we compare to the others.
We need to perform a lot of processing scenes, selecting the building blocks, converting the image
from RGV to age ASCII and also generate and realizing the histogram.
Just a reminder that the histogram will be used to perform the comparison between the frames, so the
algorithm will be able to track the object.
Now we need to define another variable parameters.
As the name suggests, this variable will star the parameters of the ME shift outwards.
And we will define parameters see ritual.
The first one is the term criteria EPS.
Then we can type this bar to the correct area counts.
Now we need to define the values for each one of them.
So our first one will be then we will copy number down to the first parameter.
And the second parameter will be one.
This value will be copied should these or other parameter, and we got this value from the documentation
of or basically we are using the default values.
We start from this point a year until year, adds should this central point.
The parameters simulate this flow until we get the object we want to track their height or devalue more
accurate to the algorithm is, however, the higher the value.
This lowered the algorithm is so if you don't have good results with the algorithm, you can try to
increase this value.
So the tendency is that the results will be better.
And regarding this second parameter, it indicates how sensible the algorithm is regarding changes in
the object.
For example, if in the first frame the object is close to the camera and in the next frame, the object
is fired from the camera.
This parameter will control the movements the object can make during the execution of the algorithm.
If you specify a big number here.
The algorithm won't be able to detect the changes in the object and similar to it.
Yes, you may try some values according to the type of video you are working with.
Now, let's implement the while loop travel through each one of the frames of the web.
We will create the variable.
OK and frame cap that reads We are reading the next frame of the web.
Similar to what we implemented using videos, if OK equals true, if we can access the next frame of
the video, then we will perform all the steps of the algorithm.
The first one we need to convert the frame that is coming from the web come from our view.
Be sure HSV spiritual severity, color frame see each quarter.
Be our true age as V.
This is the first step because we need to put the current frame with the same four months off.
All right.
Just a reminder that we first select the object, then we converts should these crawl space.
So we need to keep this same format and we'll create another variable the C ritual.
And let's call an open C v function.
Calc back.
Garage yet, and I will stand to hear age as it is the current frame.
We are going to use only one channel.
Now we will stand here.
Roy Hurst, it is this variable here which called daisy formation about the histogram of the object,
which one should track.
So we are comparing the current frame with the object want should track.
It is this part.
Here we are comparing the original histogram of the object we are tracking with the current frame of
the video.
In short, this function will calculate the PDF or, in other words, the probability density function.
And now we need to specify the order parameters the interval zero to one hundred and eighty.
And the last parameter is this k of the image.
We will put one here.
So we will keep this same scale of the image.
We are not going to perform changes on the original image.
And in case you want to know more detail about these open funsho, you can follow this link.
Now we are going to call the mini shift where Adam will recreate OK.
Variable and also the track window, which will be equal to see which means shift.
And we are going to send here the.
The calculation that is called bearing the histogram of the object with the current frame.
And then we need to specify either X, Y, W and H, which is the position of the object.
We can take a look at these variables that were defined the year, which are equal to the boarding box.
So we are sending the position of the object.
And finally, the last parameter is this variable we define see here with the values for the HEEPS and
decoupled parameters.
This code is quite similar to this one here.
Tracker dots update where we are updating the position of the objects in the webcam and this is a key
variable will bear was if the algorithm was able to update the position of the building blocks.
Now we will recreate the variables X, Y W and H equals drag window.
We are updating the position of the object.
Now we can draw a rectangle switcher that rectangle frame, which is the image that is coming from the
webcam x y the initial position x plus w y plus h the color of the ball inbox zero, two, five, five
and zero and this size of the building blocks equals two.
Now we can draw the image I am show less Typekit here.
The name of the window means shift tracking the frame if see which way key equals 13, which means the
task key on the keyboard, then we break.
The is crucial and we have implemented these if you're at the top.
If we can continue reading the frames, then we can execute the mean shift algorithm.
Otherwise, if there is errors while you reading the frames.
We can just finish the execution of the Y.
Look at the and see the chalk destroy all windows and also tap dot release to release the memory.
Finally, let's perform the test.
I will run this.
But the first step is just select the building blocks.
I will select this is my one brass and third.
And now we can see that the algorithm is already working.
I can move the pan and the algorithm is dragging the pan using means shift even when the ban is in front
of my face.
The algorithm is still tracking the pan so we can see that we have good results that are two problems
with this algorithm.
The first one, if I move the band very quick, you can see that the algorithm cannot track kids anymore.
And if I move the band again near debugging blocks, we can the new tracking the object.
And the other problem is that if I put the band near the camera, we can see that the algorithm has
good results.
But the size of the building blocks is exactly the same as the initial position.
On the other hand, when they boards the band far from the camera.
We can see that the building blocks keeps the same size and we can implement an additional code.
Let's Typekit here.
See?
Sure, I am sure I will go to hear the DSD, which is the result of the probability being set differential.
And let's Typekit here DSD.
Let's run the algorithm again.
Let's select the building blocks grass and there, and we can see this order screen here, which is
the probability density function.
See that when I move the band, we keep the aspect of the object, which is the probability density
function, and we can visualize this type of results because the algorithm is based on Calder's.
See that when they boards the fan in front of my face, we can clearly see the band.
And even when they boards the band in the background of the video, it is possible to track and you
see the difference between the object and the other parts of the image.
We know that the band is yellow and my face has a different color, so we can see this contrast with
my face and the object one should track.
This is another kind of visualization for this algorithm.
Each tries to simulate this part here.
When we are calculating the density of the data points and the next lecture, you are going to learn
another algorithm that will increase or decrease the size of the balloting box.
According should the positioning of the object see you there.