Hello and welcome to This Week lecture where you were going to learn the basic intuition about the calm
shift algorithm, which is an improvement on the main shift you learned before we added this three ladders
C, A and M, which means continuously adaptive means shift less lecturer.
We perform some tasks using means shift and evolving box was always the same size, whether the object
is near or far from the camera.
If you remember the practical implementation when we move to the band, the size of the body box was
always the same.
The main feature of this new algorithm is that the building blocks will update according to the size
of the object if it is close to the camera.
The building blocks will be larger, while the building blocks will be smaller if the object is far
from the camera.
It is a dynamic process which gives the more quality for tracking with respect to mathematics.
It also uses average calculations like the May Shift algorithm.
This image shows how the algorithm works.
We can see this red rectangle that is the equation of the mean shift going through the image when the
region of interest is found.
The yellow rectangle here, this circle will be created, so it will increase the size of the building
blocks.
See that in the first runs, the building blocks is small, and after increasing the size, the algorithm
manages to select the entire face of the person, as we can see here.
For this reason, it is possible to track objects far or close to the camera.
If you want to know more details, you can follow each step of the algorithm.
Reading these messages that appear in each change of state, for example, may shift 1st, 2nd and 3rd
right for the ellipsis generation and so on.
This is the basic information about kinship, and in the next lecture, we will implement it and perform
some tests to compare the results with the mean shift algorithm.
See you there!