Hello and welcome to this lecture, where you were going to learn the basic intuition about another
algorithm, which is optical flow, which considers the direction and speeds off peak cells.
It is similar to the motion model you learn in the first lectures that indicate where the object will
be in the next frame.
It considers location blue's speed and previous frames.
For example, the farther the car is from the camera, the smaller the movement of the pixels is because
as the image is smaller, there are less pixels in the image.
If the car is here at the ends of the image where I am pointing the mouse, its size will be much smaller
and the amount of pixels will also be smaller.
In other words, when the size of the car is smaller, that are fewer pixels to track.
On the other hand, when the car is closer to the camera, the object is bigger and there are more big
sales to be tracked, so the movements of the big cells will be greater.
In short, the closer the object is from the camera, the greater is the variation of the pixels like
the mean shift algorithm.
Optical flow also uses HSV color representation.
As you can see in this image, leather age, which means you is used to indicate the direction of the
pixels where they are moving.
These aero can point to the right, left or now.
While the -- ladder, the saturation is used to indicate the speeds of the pixels.
If the object is moving slowly, the saturation will be low from frame to frame.
On the other hand, if the object is moving quickly, the saturation will be high between frames.
Finally, leather year, the value indicates the intensity of the colors.
The closer the object is to the camera, the greater things that the of the colors, the farther away
the object is from the camera, the less intense the colors are.
We can see the definitions here.
Age is used to indicate the direction of the big cells where each pixel is moving and saturation leather
s is used to indicate this feeds off the pixels.
Now we will take a look at the optical flow algorithm.
Considering the sparse version, there are two versions of this algorithm sparse and dense, and in
this lecture, we will focus only on the sparse version of the optical flow algorithm.
Looking at this animation is easier to understand how the algorithm works.
The more movements in the image, they bigger the arrows.
They are closer to the camera.
On the other hand, delays movements in the image.
This smaller drops, they are farther from the camera.
We can see this car here further away with a small arrow, and these are their car close to the camera
with a large arrow.
We can see the same pattern here on the poles and on their roads.
For example, this small here and big here on the roads.
In short, the closer to the camera, the more motion will be detected.
To calculate how much the pixels are moving, we can use this equation at time, be the current frame
and adds time.
The plus one the next frame.
This calculation is related to the pixel intensity.
The Z channel of the HSV representation.
And here we can see that's the big slow is moving to the left and with the intensity decreasing these
peaks, so is more intense than.
These two big cells here now where we will see some mathematical calculations that are used in this
algorithm, it is important to understand because we are going to use them in the implementation.
Initially, the algorithm detects corners and edges to get their mind the orientation of the vectors
using an algorithm called Harris Gardner detector.
It is important to emphasize that in this is that the algorithm will select only some corners of the
image and not the complete object.
For example, see, that's in this car where I am pointing the mouse.
There is only one arrow and lots of bounding box around the entire object.
The algorithm will choose a corner of this image to track.
The image will not be processed big, so by Pixel, the algorithm will select only one corner of the
object.
Here you can see the equation considering X and Y axis of the image, and also that you and the parameters
of the H.
S V matrix.
These parameters indicate the movements of the big cells and leather I indicates the peak so intensity.
The purpose of the algorithm is to find values for you and Z to know the direction of the arrow.
The Arrows Considering this image, then we have the calculation of the matrix determinant, which is
an algebra concept.
According to these order equation, these words that's here and then we get the results in ladder art.
So the first step of the algorithm is to find the initial corners to start tracking.
This symbol here indicate the highest value, and this other one indicates this section's highest value.
And don't worry about understanding these complex calculations.
The idea is just to see the basic equations should be easier to understand the implementations.
Researchers Sheet and Stormzy modified the original equation and created a simplified version.
According to these other equation, here, instead of using the Matrix, they use the calculation of
the minimum between the highest value and this second highest value.
Just a reminder that this calculation will predict if a peak so is that corner or edge of an object?
This calculation is performed for all peak cells, and the computational cost is high.
So all pensively uses the concept of pyramids called K L.
The methods cannot.
Lucas and Tomasi, the name of the researchers, which are three different methods, combines and it
will analyze the smaller images of this same frame.
It is easier to understand by looking at this image.
This bottom part is the whole image.
Each layer square is up big, so we can count them one two three four five six seven eight and one two
three four five six six rows and eight Carlos multiplying both values six times eight.
Their result is for the eight pixels, and we can take a look at this part.
Here we have one short three four and one two three four times three equals 12.
So from Florida, eight big cells, the image has been reduced to only 12 pixels and then from 12 pixels.
The image has been reduced to only four pixels.
And finally, for all four big cells, the image.
She has been reduced to only one peak, so.
So the image is smaller and the calculation will be faster.
On the left, we have the image and style there.
And on the right, we have the image at times b plus one because rents.
And then next frame of the video after the image size is reduced, the optical flow is calculated from
top to bottom.
As you can see the arrows and the goal is to find values for you and envy that will indicate the direction
of the arrows or the direction of the object.
In short, for the image, dimensions are reduced and then their frames are going backwards using the
reversed versions of the images.
The process is starts at I three.
I show I one.
And finally I zero, which is the number of layers to process the image.
That's all for the basic intuition.
In the next lecture we will implement, it's using open Sivy and then it will be easier to understand
some of these concepts.
See you there!