Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to finish the implementation of the optical flow
spa's algorithm.
Just a reminder that last lecture we defined the parameters we are using parameters sheet Tomasi and
then we are sending the parameters.
Should this function, good features should track and we are also sending the first frame of the video.
The algorithm will detect 38 corners are thirty eight points.
We can see here the position of the points, the X and Y axis.
The tracking will start by these points here, where we are going to go through each one of the frames
of the video.
Let's implement the while loop.
OK.
And frame cap that reads We are reading each frame of the video.
Now we need to convert the frame to grayscale.
Let's create the new variable frame rate, spiritual severity, koala.
Let's send the original frame in the RGV format and let's convert koala BGR to sugary.
This is the same code we implemented here, and we also saw the results.
Now I will create three new variables new edges start those and errors.
They will be equal to see visual.
Now we call the optical flow algorithm, we can use the function calc.
OK, goal flow b, why are Al K, which means the k l the methods they cannot.
Lucas and Tomasetti.
That's mathematical calculations that will use the concepts of pyramids.
So it's important to emphasize that in the first part of the algorithm, we only get the coroners,
the initial coroners, and now we are using these methods in order to reduce this size of the image
using the concept of parameters.
And these parts of the algorithm that will track the objects.
Just a reminder.
We can assume that this part here is the current frame and the right bards is the next frame of the
video.
Blathers L K means Lucas can eight.
And now we need to specify some parameters.
The first one is frame grey units.
The first frame of the video.
Just a reminder that we are extracting the initial edges from this frame here.
Then the X parameter is frame grey, the current frame, so the calculations can be done using both
four frames, the current and the initial.
We are simulating these calculations between the images here, the pyramids.
We also need to sand the edges that were found in the first frame of the video.
Lorne is a parameter related to the mask.
We are not going to use it.
And finally, let's sand here parameter Lucas cannot this variable we defined here with this size of
the window and also with the Level R, the number of layers in the pyramids, we can open this single
tracking file just a reminder that we first initialize the algorithm.
And then after each one of the frames, we get a new balding box calling the update function.
This part is quite similar.
First, we get the initial edges and this function will perform the calculations in order to track our
full update to the points, they can look here that we are sending the initial edges that were found
in the first frame of the video and then.
This variable new edge will get to the next position of the objects are the next position of the edges.
In short, we are updating the positions.
This variable will control if we can keep track the object, it will return one.
If the algorithm can continue tracking the object and zero indicate that the algorithm cannot track
the object anymore, and we can also see some error messages.
We are not going to use this variable.
Let's create the news variable, which will be equal to new edges, the new X and Y position of each
one of the corners, and we need to get the ones with state those equals one.
So it means we can keep tracking the edge.
Let's create the old variable, which will be equal to X.
Also, that those equals one.
Both variables are used to simulate this part here.
We can consider that old is this variable.
The previous position off the edge and new is this part here?
The next position of the edge.
So then we can apply the optical flow calculations in order to find you and the values that will indicate
the next direction of the coroner or the next direction of the object.
As there are 38 points considering this frame, we need to go through each one of this points to visualize
their results because these while loop is going through each one of the frames and we are tracking 38
objects are 38 coroners in each one of the frames.
So we need to implement a model loop here for a new and old show variables.
I'm creating now in enumerate and now we need to go through Neo's and all variable.
Each one of the thirty eight values show each one of these variables here.
As we are accessing two variables in the far loop, we need to add this code here Zip Nils and Oates
so we can get the values of both variables at this same far loop.
Let's get to the points.
A B equals new dot ratio.
This code is used to convert a matrix into a vector.
Let's Grade C and the points holds the travel variable A and B where we start.
The new value are the new position of the coroner, on the other hand.
C and D variables, we start the previous position of the coroner.
Let's create another variable mask CV tube line mask.
Let's send here a and B the new position C and D the previous position.
Let's sexists collars to position, i.e. when we use enumerate function, we are going to copy to the
AI variable.
The current is it show off the far loop.
For example, in the first time we run this far loop variable, I will be equal to zero, then it will
be equal to one, two, three and so on, and we are going to use this variable to access this list
of colors.
Just a reminder that we are initializing at random collars in order to print each one of the gardeners
with a different color.
And in this variable mask, we just needs to convert to the list for months and this size of delight
in.
Some minutes, we're going to see the results of this function, but in short, it will draw a line
to follow the object similar to this one here so we can see where the object is moving.
Let's access the frame servitude.
But let's draw a circle in each one of the points frame position A and B.
Five Is this size colors.
Position I will list and the thickness of the circle minus one, after processing the points and drawing
the results in the video, I will create a new variable.
You might see richer dots at Frame and Musk and then sift through.
I am sure the title of the window.
Optical flow spa's.
And let's put here I am the new variable.
This is an open civil codes to keep the results of both variables in the same window, so we are adding
them instead of using.
Sure, I am sure we can odds both windows to show both results.
The line and this circle.
If spiritual weight Q one equals 13.
It means the +3 button in the keyboards, then we will break the equation.
And finally frame grey units equals frame grey dots copy.
This is a very important codes because at the first is inclusion, we are using the first frame of the
video to initialize the algorithm.
However, when we keep processing the video, we need to compare the previous frame with the next frame.
So we need to keep updating.
This variable at the first is a commercial.
We will get to hear the first frame of the video, but when we go through to the second, to the third
to define our frame of the video, we needs to update using the frame gray.
So in this section is crucial of the far loop.
The frame gray needs will be equal to the previous frame, and we will compare it with the current frame
of the video, always making this spider image calculation.
The previous and the current, the previous and the current.
And finally, we also need to update Edge is variable because take a look here that we have the initial
position off the corners and we need to update according to the new position.
Similar should this concept here, the frame gray in it.
So now we can just spot here miles.
And in order to have in the correct formats, let's type reshape minus one, one and two just two boards
in the correct format.
Choose Sans should the optical flow function here.
And after the while loop switcher destroy all windows and cap really is to release memory.
Now let's run the code and perform the first test, and we can see one year or a year in the line function
and it happens on the line and also in this circle function.
Because this A, B, C and D are floats and we need to code words to integers.
So we just need to type in A and B and C and D and here and A and ends B.
Now we can run the codes again.
We can open the window and we can see our results.
We can take a look at a lot of corners that were detected.
Some of them are not moving like these ones in the car and in some parts of the grass here.
And there is no problem about it, because as we discussed before, the goal of this implementation
is to detect the 38 coroners in the first frame of the video and then we can track them.
We could see that some of the points were related to people moving so we could draw that line tracking
all the movement of the person during the entire video and when the processing of the video.
And you may see one ear horror here at the console and it is happening in this line here when we are
trying to convert the frame to greyscale.
And it happens because it's missing an important code here.
If not, OK, if we are not able to read the frame, then we can just break this.
While loop through is stop is a good thing, we can try to run this code again just to make sure that
this error is not being returned anymore.
After processing the frames, the Ihor is not appearing, so now our code is OK and we can take a look
at this part here.
Just a reminder that we are in the frame and also the mask instead of showing I am the new variable.
We can just show the original frame.
Let's run the codes again, and we can see only the coroners this year course.
It is related to this implementation.
Here we are detecting the points are the gardeners and we are drawing this circle together with the
object.
We can also take a look at the mask.
Just a reminder that this variable is composed of only zeros which are related to the black caller.
Let's run the code again, and we can see a very interesting visualization.
We can see the lines according to the movement of the objects and see these other points here with no
movement.
And you combine both of them.
We can use the image.
Run this code again and we can see the corners and also the lines, according to the movement of the
objects.
And that's all for this first implementation.
And in the next lecture, we are going to select the object that one should track instead of generating
the edges, according should the algorithm see you there.