Hello and welcome to this lecture that we are going to implement another example using optical flow
spurs in the last implementation.
We just initialize the algorithm with the partners that were detected in the first frame of the video.
And now the goal is to select the initial coroner.
So we will be able to select the object we want to track and we will implement it using the web cam.
We already have these optical flows bars to file already implemented with these initial codes.
We are implanting open SIFI melt by connecting to the web cam, and then we are reading the first frame
of the video and converting it to Grayscale.
Also, our defining the parameters regarding Lucas cannot just to recap this to first.
I mean, there's the wing size means the big cells of the pyramids and max level means that the pyramid
has four layers and we are using the same parameters as before eps and count.
Now we will define a new function.
So we will be able to select a point when the web is open.
Let's great select point.
It will receive as a parameter the event X and Y coordinates flags and also firearms.
And this is an open civil function that we are going to execute.
Let's define some global variables so they can be axis three.
All these crucial of the program points.
Select this point and also all these points.
If the event equals servitude and we can type here events l button down, it means that we are clicking
the left button of the mouse.
It is a kind of a trigger when we press the left button off the mouse.
The code that we are going to implement now will be executed, which will be equal to X and Y.
It means the coordinates on the screen that are coming from these parameters here.
When we click in my specific position of the window, the coordinates will be copied to this variable
here.
So this selected point will be equal to withdraw.
So it means that points are accordingly to was selected.
Let's access all these points variable and be array LES converts to these formats x y and this type
will be equal to flows through.
In short, we will keep the current point and also the previous point.
This is the only limitation regarding this function.
And now we need to associate associated with the window.
Let's Typekit here.
See your main window and the name of the window that we are going to create will be frames.
Signature sets mouse all back, and let's Typekit here fray the name off the window and select wines.
The name of the function.
So we are associating this function should these local frame, every time we create a window with this
name, it will be possible to execute this function to get to the point.
According to the left, the bottle now evens on the mouse.
Now when we create this select, this quite variable equals false.
It demands that no wine twice selected.
See that this variable has this same name as defined here, so it means that we are accessing this same
variable.
SEALs it is a global variable.
Let's create the white variable with this same name and an empty variable at the beginning, and old
wines will be equal to empty array empty points.
We are just initializing this variable and we are going to change the values when we run this function.
Let's create the mask variable and be zeros like frames.
This same variable we had defined earlier.
Now we'll just base that code because it is quite similar to the one we implement before they can look
here that we are going through each one of the frames.
We are really in the frame.
If we can't redo the next frame, we're interrupted.
The equation converts to grayscale and the only difference is that we are checking the value of this
variable here that is initialized with force.
And when we click with the left, but off the mouse, the value changes through.
So it demands that apply to was selected and if applied, why select selected BAM?
We run all the code.
We implement it before we draw a circle on the point.
We get the new blinds.
This code is updating the location of the point.
We send the Here DeLuca's can aid parameters.
We make a copy of the frame star or the old point.
Here we get the clearance and the next location we create the mask, the frame.
And here we are, adding the frame and the mask.
The same code we have before.
Here we have another difference ID number twenty seven means the ASCII.
So when we press asked this quotient, we'll be interrupted.
Let's run this code.
We can't see one, eight or so.
It sure has no attributes the main window because we need to change here to name the window.
And also, let's change here, callback with lower case ladder.
Now we can run this code.
Let's open the window to test the algorithm where we use the ban again.
Then you can click with the left button of the mouse.
Take a look that applying to was generated, and now we can start tracking the object.
The interesting point is that this line is generated according to the movement of the band when they
put the ban in front of my face.
The algorithm continued tracking, and if you click again with the left button, a new light will be
generated so you can track the new object.
And here we are showing AMG, which is the combination of the frame and the mask.
We can command to these codes to show only the mask.
Let's run the code again that are truly in those.
Let's select the point and drag the object.
We can see here.
Only the lines that are generating according to the movements of the band.
So it is an interesting view to see the roots, that's the object is going.
And that's all for this lecture about optical flow spires in the next one.
You are going to learn the basic intuition and mainly the differences between optical flow is sparse
and optical flow dense, and right after we are going to move back to the implementations.
See you there.