Hello and welcome to this lecture, where you are going to learn the basic intuition about another type
of the optical flow algorithm, which is the dance, as you can read, the here.
The one you learned before was the optical flow sparse.
All mathematical concepts and calculations, especially the concept of pyramids, are the same.
And we will only see what is different.
The main difference is that sparse optical flow detects the coroner's only in the first frame, while
dance uses the full image.
Therefore, it is is a lower birth generally gives bad results in shards in this bar's algorithm.
The coroners are detected only in the initial frame.
And these same iguanas are used during the entire is it crucial, while in the dance algorithm, the
coroners are detected frame by frame.
There are several ways to implement this algorithm, and the one that's OpenSea uses is the fender back
methods, which uses a linear algebra concept called polynomial expansion.
We will see more detail about this name here in the implementations to understand the differences between
the two techniques spires and dance.
We can look at this image on the left is espoirs, and on your right is dance as we can see and implement
it before spa's gets a few pixels that represent the edges and the corners of the image.
And then it is possible to draw a line that indicates the path of the object, which is nothing more
than tracking something that is that's generally the object is not selected on the order of hands.
The dance algorithm lets you select the entire object, as you can see here is possible to see the shape
of the.
Earlier, I command the.
It's that the quality could be bad there, and we can see that this pass cannot drag.
Could this yellow car here?
Whereas the dance algorithm can, as you can see here, where I am pointing the mouse Big Color is more
intense for objects close to the camera.
For example, for this car here and less in bands for objects fired from the camera here on the bridge.
If the object is not moving, it is not detected.
This bar's algorithm is tracking here the edge of the roads on the order of hands.
Here, the image is black, indicating that the edge of the road will not be tracked.
And that's all for the basic differences between the algorithms.
In the next lecture, we are going to implemented using open SIFI sealed air.