Hello and welcome to this lecture, where we are going to implement optical flow dance algorithm.
We have this quote with some implementations.
First, we are implanting open Siri and by then we are loading it walking video in this folder, here
we get the first frame of the video.
Then we are converting the first frame to Grayscale.
After that, we create the age HSV matrix, which will be composed of zeros.
And we are sending the first frame.
So it means that we want to generate a matrix with this same size of the first frame.
Just a reminder that the optical flow algorithm uses the HSV color space.
Let's run this code and check these sprints.
The first when we are in the dimensions of the first frame of the walk in the video, take a look here
that we can see the dimensions and the number of channels.
And then we are printing the dimensions of the HSV matrix that we generated here.
We can see that it has this same size since we are going to use it later to print the results.
In the video we can see here the first frame with the original pixels of the image from zero to 200
and 55.
We can also prints HSV.
Let's run this code again.
And we can take a look that we have only zeros, which means the black color.
Let's put all this prints in comments.
Now we are going to axis HSV matrix.
I will put three dots here because as we can see, that are three dimensions and we need two axis position
number one.
And the value will be two hundred and fifty five.
As we know, the HSV color space has three values.
B who led the H, which is used to indicate the direction of the B cells and it is position number zero.
Then we have this saturation leather -- that is used to indicate the speeds of the pixels, which is
position number one and the value is position number two.
When we type this code referring to position number one, it means that we are changing the value of
this saturation.
So this saturation is initialized with the maximum value, which means the maximum and things should
be.
We can brents again.
HSV matrix.
Run this code again and we can see that we have changed only position number one position zero keeps
zero position.
Chuir also keeps with values zero.
We have changed only this saturation, which is position number one.
Now let's implement the Y.
You look to go through each one of the frames.
OK, frame equal.
Yep, that reads trades the next frame of the video.
Let's convert the current frame grayscale switcher civility color.
Let's send the frame that was red from the web cam switcher color BGR sugary.
And then let's create a new variable.
I will call it S Flow.
I will use an open C V Function Calc Optical Flow firing back as you learns in the tuition lecturer,
there are some ways to implement optical flow dance and there weren't that open v uses is defender back
Eq..
So we are using this implementation if you want to know more.
Views about the parameters that we are going to set now, you can follow these documentation lead from
open CV.
The first parameter is frame gray in its the first frame of the video, and then we need to compare
your frame gray, which is the current frame.
We can take a look at the documentation here, see that we are sending the previous frame and the next
frame, and it is needed because of all calculations regarding the pyramids that you learned before.
Then the experiment there is flow and we will set it as non and we will have a value for this parameter
when there is a predefined direction of the arrows and it is needed another output array.
And as we don't have these other array, we can set it as none.
The next parameter will be zero point five and it is related to the scale of the pyramids.
We can take a look at the documentation here, and the default value is zero point five, which means
a classical pyramid where each next layer is twice is smaller than the previous one.
Let's suppose this size of one layer is 30 pixels, and this size of the other layer will be twice as
smaller.
So this size will be equal to 10 pixels and then the next layer this size will be about three pixels.
The next perimeter three, which means the levels of the pyramids, for example, in this image that
are four levels and we are defining parameters with three levels.
The next parameter 15, which is related should the window size regarding the number of pixels in the
layers, and we will keep one thing which is the default value.
Then the experimenter number three, which is the number of iterations the algorithm does at each pyramid
level.
In other words, it is the number of repetitions are calculations in each level.
The next parameter equals five, which is related should the concept of polynomial expansion, because
the dance of the flow uses this mathematical equation.
And in other words, it is this size of the peak.
So neighborhoods used to find the polynomial spatial in each pixel, and you can see the recommendations
for this parameter.
Typically, while an equals five are equals seven, as you can see, we are using the default parameters.
The next one weren't quite sure.
That means the ball is sigma, which is the standard deviation, and there is this recommendation here.
If poorly and equals five, we can set wireless sigma one point one and if only an equal seven, then
we can try one point five.
We can just change to one point one here, and the last parameter equals zero, which means the flags
and we are using this first option.
Here it will.
We use the input flow.
The initial frame as initial flow approximation.
It means that we are using the first frame of the video after setting the parameters.
Now we need to perform some additional calculations and we will create sure new variables, the magnitude
and the angle which will be equal.
Cho Seung-Hui Cho dockyards cho polar.
This is an open city function.
Cho gets both values here to know the direction of the arrows to predict where the object is going or
the direction, and we will stand here as parameter flow.
We will put three dots here again, position zero and flow again three dots because we have a three
dimensional matrix position.
One is shards.
Both values represent the X and Y axis, the position of the object.
We can open the optical flow spires and we can take a look at this variable here.
New edges, which is the new position of the coroner and this code is similar.
Their results of this function will be in this flow variable here.
So in the first position, we get the magnitudes.
And in this second position, we get the angle, which in short, are the X and Y axis.
Now in this axis, our H s v matrix and now our wheel axis positions zero.
We already know that's a position.
Number one is this saturation that we initialized with the maximum value two hundred and fifty five.
Now we are going to axis the whole, which is used to indicate the direction of the peak cells or that
arrow.
If the arrow is pointing to the left to the right and so on, and it will be equal should the angle
lines one hundred and eighty divided by and B dots.
I this is the pie number used in calculus.
And let's divide by two.
Don't worry about all these calculations because it is an algebra equation to find the direction of
the arrow.
It deals with degrees, and now we need to axis the value, which is in position number two, which
is the thing city of the Pixel and we will call the function normalize.
Let's send here the magnitudes.
No, on the second barometer, the revolt, the values are from zero to 200 and 55 and civic ma'am naam
min max.
Basically, it was issue number two.
We are just normalizing the magnitudes.
Now we will create another variable frame.
RGV, which will be equal, should see future civility.
The Kuala Age as V and let's convert from H.
S V to BGR because we have this gallery space in the age matrix, which is used to perform the calculations
regarding the optical flow algorithm.
But in order to see the results on this screen, we need to convert again to RG B and now we can show
the results signature.
I am sure the title of the window bounce optical flow frame are good b if see which way key equals 13.
If we press another band, we will break the execution.
And finally, we need to shoot up the eight frame gray in its equals frame rate because we always need
to compare the previous frame with the next frame at the man's cop thought release.
Syria to destroy all windows, to release the memory.
Just an additional quote here, if not, OK, then we can break the execution.
Now let's run these codes.
We can open the window and take a look here that this is a different way to track the objects we are
running the walking video, which presents people walking on that streets so we can see the color spaces
here with information about the people.
We can see that we have good results.
We can track each one of the people in this video.
And that's all about the implementation of optical flow downs.
See you next time.